hey guys if you're not subscribed please
smash that subscribe button and hit that
like button on the video and if you
don't have time to watch this episode
right now no problem but I'd really
appreciate it if you would save it to
your watch later playlist finally if
you'd like to follow me on Instagram and
X those links are in my description
below thank you so I said to Carrie this
is 2009 the pakistanis arrested that
doctor they charged him with before he's
killed cuz he's killed in 2011 correct
right so I said we should get him out
and bring it back to the United States
oh cuz you knew that you were read in on
the intelligence that they confirmed it
was him you knew about bin L's
whereabouts 2 years before it happened
and you weren't even in CIA anymore yeah
how do you
[Music]
know what about the other one though you
know what one I'm going to ask
about which one the files the ones that
were just magically shut from everyone
at the end of 2021 at the end of gilan
Maxwell's trial oh that you know I
almost forgot about that talk about
literally no reason to be
classified and another thing you know
Epstein's black book do I know I've read
it cover it's sold it's sold at auction
the original sold at auction and the
photocopy out there for people to see
why would we be protecting a guy like
him why he's a convicted pet first of
all and probably way worse than just
that yes I think the evidence is pretty
strong that he was way worse than that
bad bad guy I say all all the time and
I'm going to repeat it here I think the
reason why even in death he's being
protected is I believe pretty strongly
that he's a he was a mosad access agent
as do I it it it all points to that so
why are we protecting him yeah exactly
why are we protecting him uhhuh that's
why you were here please answer I mean
well look look at why the Mad might be
interested in somebody like him let's
say you are the leader of the mad and
you want really tightly held closely
protected information from senior
American leaders political leaders
Business Leaders you can't recruit those
people you're not going to recruit Bill
Clinton you're not going to recruit uh
Bill Gates or you know any of the other
PE prince Andrew you're not going to
recruit those people so you do the next
thing you recruit somebody who has ready
access to that that's right and then on
top of that you give them an unlimited
amount of money where he's got this
private island in the Caribbean and a
private jet where he can fly his friends
down there you wire the house for audio
and video so nothing is uh is overlooked
and you ply them with alcohol and
underage girls and you've got them
you've got them so you can either do it
the easy way or you can do do it the
hard way you say to them look you just
had 16-year-old girl and so you're going
to tell me what I want to know
or they know what the game is they know
what they've done otherwise we wouldn't
have people coming out and saying well I
kept my underwear on remember that
uhhuh so I think that that's what this
was I think that this is because we all
know that the Israelis spy on us I mean
they're they're worse than the KGB or
whatever the KGB we're going to talk
about that yeah yeah they're they're for
for the intelligence community of the
United States Israel is ranked as
critical threat for Counter Intelligence
they are prolific spies and so um I I it
just makes perfect sense to me that this
would be an access operation so again
though why are we the ones saying nope
NOP nope closed up cuz let me let me
paint a picture for you real quick and
you tell me if I'm way off here I I
don't I don't care if I'm off it's just
what I think about sometimes and I've I
remember my first conversation I ever
had with Danny Jones on the phone we
talked about this and that I've had this
thought for probably four or five years
I want you to imagine you're sitting in
a
room a back room in Israel in 1967 or
1968 okay you just had the whole 1967
thing pop off right you were just over
20 years removed from the Holocaust
where your race was attempted to be
exterminated from this Earth You are
still four years out for the Munich
Olympics where people are going to put
their hands up and not help you or not
let you even come in and help the
situation when your people were
kidnapped and the games actually
continued they didn't even pause while
it was going on that's right so that's
not even on the table yet but you
realize that there's a lot of support
around the world that isn't necessarily
coming to your Aid in your defense you
are a small country in the middle of the
Middle East where every at the time
every single country around you would
like you eradicated from the earth and
in this room is only a hand full of
people it's like golden my ear the
leader maybe the the definitely the head
of mad maybe the head of Shin Bet m one
or two other people and you were sitting
around and mind you in America we think
about everything tomorrow the day after
that maybe if we're a real long-term
thinker we're thinking about next year
Point good point other places around the
world they think two 300 years out
certain places around the world they're
thinking thousands of years out and when
you have something like you know the
Jewish people who have been persecuted
throughout time stuck together very well
who just witnessed an Extinction event
happen they are thinking thousands of
years out to make this last their
population have been decimated that's
why the hdic Jews have so many children
yeah it's to repopulate another great
example so you have that thought in mind
and mean and I say this because you're
not thinking about what is Israel look
like in 1987 you're thinking about what
Israel looks like in
3027 and what your people the diaspora
looks like around the world and you say
to yourself it's not math it's now a
mathematical analytical trade-off that's
why you're in this job you say to
yourself
okay how do we ensure our survival
thousands of years from now well we got
one place that's a great friend America
but they are geographically separated
from us and we're having some trouble
getting them to come over here and help
us on certain issues we've had some
tough back Channel Communications with
them it's not really working as well as
we want and we know the people in Europe
are good for nothing so how do we make
sure America is our best friend well you
know this is the dawn of the TV age it's
where pop culture kind of all comes
together it's post Kennedy who was a pop
culture president you have politics you
have entertainment you have media you
have you know business all these things
are interchangeable and you say okay we
need to make sure we get close to these
people and we need to make sure that
when we get close to these people you
know we have some information that can
make sure that they're there for us when
we need them and so they sit around the
room and they say right what's one thing
people can't come back from and someone
raises their hand and they say murder
and they're like no no that's been done
before people have come back from that
you can come back from that and then
someone in the room says and you got to
bleep this cesie
kid and everyone in the room knows that
this is a first world country we're
talking about and that's a big no no you
don't come back from that you do that
you're cooked it's not possible you're
cooked MH and they sit there and they
say maybe they don't say it like this
but they say are we willing to
sacrifice the lives effectively of
50,000 kids over the next five six
decades to make sure that our entire
race survives a thousand years from
now and in the words Alo rain I'll make
that deal right like that's the attitude
that the people in those rooms have and
that's not a deal I want to make to be
clear I'm not saying about myself right
I'm saying this is how they might think
I could see that is that far-fetched no
I could see that I could see that their
calculation is far different than our
calculation would be you're right about
about long-term versus short-term we
only look to you know the end of the the
current president's term we don't do
long-term planning we never have we
pretend to like on nuclear stock piles
and stuff like that but we don't really
do long-term planning they do very
long-term planning and that's why that's
why there's such prolific spies um I
remember on my first day at the CIA and
I think I told you this before um we
were in the it's called the bubble the
cia's auditorium
and all the new hires like hundreds of
us and uh we were getting briefings like
the the head of security would come and
brief us and the head of HR and the head
of this and the head of that and
whatever and the head of Counter
Intelligence came to brief us and said
he explained what a declared officer was
versus a unilateral officer so a
unilateral officer is you're undercover
overseas nobody knows your CIA a
declared officer is somebody
where like I was I was declared uh in in
Athens the the my boss took me to the
Greek intelligence service and said this
is John kyaku he's a CIA officer and
he's here to work with your people so
they've declared my status so
um he said that the Israelis have
to declared officers here uh one mad one
shinb they work in the Israeli Embassy
missing 187 though and and the FBI had
yeah the FBI had identified
189 yeah 189 Undeclared Israeli officers
Intelligence Officers and they were they
were in mostly in defense contractors
all across America trying to steal our
defense Secrets later on somebody told
me well you know the Israelis the
Israelis are
obsessed with the idea that we're not
giving them everything
right and we give them pretty much
everything but they want to make sure
they're getting everything literally
everything for example when the F35 came
out they were the first ones to say we
want the
F35 and so we said okay we'll give you
the
F35
so we just barely degraded the
avionics okay and we called it the f35i
for Israel and the reason why we did did
that is because we don't want anybody to
have exactly the avionics that we have
in case you know what happens if one of
these crashes in Russian territory and
the Russians reverse engineer now they
have the
F35 we did the same thing with the
Emirates the F35 e for Emirates so they
said no we want your F35 the same F-35
that that you have and we're like no
we're not giving it to you and we sold
them the f 35 I well they're trying to
steal the avionics for the F-35 because
we wouldn't turn it over it's very
typical of what the israelies do and
then you know at the same time they
smile and they thank you and our
friendship is is forever greatest Ally
yeah another one he should have stayed
in Philadelphia the world would be a
better place yeah he's not great no it's
here this is such a hard topic because
people have such strong opinions and and
I get yelled at by everyone on this like
a lot of things I'm pretty down the
middle on this one I fully I fully
understand why it's a state I support
that I would like a two-state solution
me too I think that Hamas and Hezbollah
are bad I also think the current
leadership of the Israeli government is
bad I think what's going on in Gaza is
terrible I understand October 7th was
was terrible and that's what started in
the first place I agree with every word
you've said Okay so let's keep going
here first of
all the million-dollar question let's
start with an easy one the f35i example
if the shoe were on the other foot will
we not do the same thing probably okay
yeah so you got to call it both ways on
this that's fair second
example not necessarily like a guy like
Epstein himself who was just so prolific
and really like he was over the top
about it like he in your face about it
it was really disgusting and pathetic
and a lot of things at the same time the
types of things he did though that
involve tring human traffing let's call
it what it
is do we ever do that
too not in my experience I ask when when
I speak at universities as part of my
standard speech I ask this question it's
a hypothetical
question um but I usually talk about
ethics and I say imagine you are a CIA
officer working overseas undercover and
you have recruited a Bonafide terrorist
Hezbollah Al-Qaeda Isis whatever it
doesn't make any difference and you meet
with him monthly in a hotel room let's
say in Aman or
Cairo and this guy has given you
actionable intelligence that you have
used to disrupt attacks against the
United States the guy's the real
deal and you go to meet him one day and
he says you know what I've given you
everything that you have wanted so today
you're going to do something for me and
I'm not giving you any more information
until you get me a prostitute right now
just a prostitute do you get him the
prostitute I said I always ask show of
hands how many people would give him the
prostitute and usually about 75% put
their hands up yeah I Pro I probably
make that deal yeah and I say yeah yeah
you would you give him the prostitute
it's it's nasty it's ugly but you know
this is the job that we've Chosen and
that's her job as long as she agreed to
it like on a business yeah okay what if
he asks you for a child prostitute yeah
I knew it was going there how many would
give him a prostitute that's where I
can't do this show and they all they all
look around and then usually about 10%
will put their hand up and I say
absolutely not not under any
circumstance
let's talk about peptides for a minute
if you're like me you're seeing them
everywhere just because something says
peptide on the label doesn't mean it's
actually doing anything for you that's
where one Skin's oso1 peptide is
different while some peptides just sit
on top of the skin oso1 goes deeper it's
scientifically formulated to penetrate
the cells within Skin's deeper layers
improving key skin Health markers like
collagen production hydration and Skin
Barrier function not only that oso1 is
proven to remain stable from the last AB
to your countertop so you get reliable
results every time listen if you're not
getting results from your peptide it
might be time to take a closer look all
of One Skin's topical supplements are
backed by lab and clinical studies and
they're all powered by the oso1 peptide
the first and only peptid scientifically
proven to Target the cisin cells that
contribute to lines wrinkles and
thinning skin try one skin to get an
exclusive 15% off your first purchase
using Code Julian onsk skin.co now my
favorite product at onkin is by far the
oso1 face topical supplement I use this
in the mornings and always at night and
it also smells really good by the way
you put it on your skin you get good
little feeling but what this does is it
helps reduce the lines on my face and
I've been using it now for I don't know
maybe like 6 weeks seven weeks something
like that and I do see a difference
obviously I got to look good on camera
so you know we need stuff like this so
go get 15% off your first order of one
skin products by using Code Julian onsk
skin.co that link is in the description
below once again that's 15% off using
Code julian1 skin.co after your purchase
they're going to ask you where you heard
about them so please support our show
and tell them Julian sent you invest in
the Health and Longevity of your skin
with one skin your future self will
thank you first of all from a practical
perspective he's not going to walk away
you're paying him thousands and
thousands of dollars for his information
you're probably willing to resettle him
if something goes
wrong but this is a child we're talking
about child the problem though is and
this is why I bring this up there's no
rule at the agency remember your job is
to break the laws of the country that
you're in you're committing Espionage
just having the meeting in the first
place so you've got to go into a career
like this with your own set of moral
values with your own ethical standards
deep down we all know right from wrong
it's really not that complicated you
know that it would be wrong to do
something like that under any
circumstances and sometimes people will
say well greater good and all that stuff
and I say no in real life he's going to
give you the information it's not about
the child he can go out and do whatever
he wants in his own time but you've got
to draw the line between right and wrong
because headquarters isn't going to do
it for you I think the incentive
structure you point out in that example
actually makes your answer make sense I
I would believe that
but on a greater mission level meaning
like if it wasn't just some guy who
you're already paying who says you know
what go get me a kid and you're like you
you're not going anywhere right if it
was something where you were trying to
infiltrate people who were involved with
this kind of thing and you needed to not
even create it yourself you mean to
disrupt a network sure uhhuh that a
network that doesn't have to do with
that but they do this too you're telling
me and I hope you're right too because I
would like to think we don't do this but
you're telling me that that would never
happen you know I can't say with 100%
certainty but I can say in the 15 years
that I was there I never encountered
anything even close yeah I couldn't see
you doing that never yeah that you
wouldn't even do the torture no I
wouldn't even do the torture one guy one
guy asked me for a ton of money and I'm
like yeah that's a lot of money and he
says well I brought all my wife's gold
jewelry I said what am I if Jeweler now
yeah come on you know the deal you
signed a contract there could it's a big
organization know and we don't know how
big it is and I I always ask that there
a lot of sociopaths walk in the halls
and you know that you know we're we're
zeroing in on Epstein here because he
was caught and he was here yeah they're
not the only ones who do that man you're
absolutely right there's a lot of
agencies that do that kind of thing
around the world a lot and that's where
it gets messy it's disgusting it's
horrible but you know the fact that we
are closing those files does tell me a
lot and it tells me that there's
influence spot you know yeah there has
to be because again there is literally
no no reason no legitimate reason for
any of those documents to be classified
none
yeah another argument that pisses me off
with this because I think people are
looking at it the wrong way is the whole
APAC thing mhm so everyone complains
about ape yeah and they blame APAC right
and they blame Israel right and I'm like
wait a minute
blame the justice department and the
Congress they're using the system sure
that we allow to be used they're of
course they're looking out for their own
country's interest it's like blaming
rich people for taking tax deductions
don't blame the rich people fix the law
exactly how why why don't we do that why
is that not changed because I mean I'm
going to be straight with you when I
look at
Trump's current cabinet there's three
positions and please correct me if I'm
wrong here that are that have the most
impact on foreign policy outside of
Tulsi gabard okay at dni you know and
and Ratcliffe at CIA there's a secretary
of state the Secretary of Defense and
the UN Ambassador and we're one of like
two countries that can veto anything yes
I got a un Ambassador stefanic who's
number one funer is Apac who goes in
front of [__] the Senate to to get
confirmed and tells van Holland did a
great job with her he didn't like try to
bury her he he knew his and she told him
to his face that she believes that that
Israel has a Biblical right to the West
Bank which is a war crime for everyone
for everyone keeping track out there I
then have a secretary of state Marco
Rubio who's funded out the by them by
yep and then I have a secretary of
defense Pete hegseth who you know not
his fault he just came from Fox News so
we can't see where he's funding but when
he's walking out of meetings with oh I
don't know John fedman a senate a
senator who's going to vote on him
what's the first thing he says I was
very glad I could sit down for the
position of United States Secretary of
Defense with the United States Senator
and discuss our greatest Ally Israel and
our unwavering support to them if my
United States Senator and my United
States Secretary of Defense number one
issue for the United States defense
department is another country they could
be the best country in the world it
could be my best friend in Britain and
like I'm not I don't with that what
about the congressman that wore a wore
an Israeli military uniform onto the
floor of the house oh yeah you're talk
what's the guy the guy with with he's
missing his leges I don't mean that I
mean way what what the hell is his name
Brian it was he was on that article we
pulled up earlier he's the guy who
announced all these things all the US
Aid funding Brian right man
or it's short not man it's you have the
linkas Mars one I texted you yeah that
guy Mass what was it Brian m m yeah Mast
he was wearing another country again I
don't have any issue like there's a lot
of positive about Israel but like if
that were a British uniform everyone
would be up in arms yeah they would be
what the yes it's
unacceptable yeah I couldn't agree more
I feel exactly the same
way and you know it's it's it pains me
too that we are so willing as a country
to just acques to genocide and even the
act of even the act
of moving Palestinians out of Gaza to
develop the land that is an act of
genocide ethnic cleansing yeah it's
ethnic cleansing exactly why is nobody
talking about this you can't do it I I
was talking to an Albanian um
documentary filmmaker just a couple of
days ago and he said you know there's
this idea being floated that they're
going to move all the Palestinians to
Albania because we're
Muslims and I'm like Albania I hadn't
heard that he said the albanians are up
in arms right now secular Muslim too
yeah there secular Muslims who don't
speak Arabic by the way yeah and uh you
know there was talk early on it came
from the White House of moving them to
this island that's owned by
Indonesia and they could speak Arabic
there and then the third idea was to
split them in half and you put half in
Jordan and half in Egypt and both the
jordanians and Egyptians said absolutely
not you know in in 68 uh in September of
68 Palestinians were fighting Jordanian
troops literally on the steps of the
Royal Palace to take Jordan for
themselves fully half of the population
of Jordan is Palestinian the king's wife
is Palestinian the king's wife is
Palestinian now what do you think of
that guy let's start there I like the
king I do too he's my favorite King he's
my favorite King too I I know we like
fought a war over that here I don't
really [__] with kings and queens but
he's you know when I was living in
London I used to see the Greek king the
exiled deposed Greek king in church on
Sunday the royal family gets the the
first row in the church and I used to
think you sorry bastards you're not even
Greek you're Danish you were imposed on
us that's right they speak German King
Otto the first othonos which isn't even
a Greek name they they heniz it uhhuh he
never he was King for 30 years he never
learned how to speak Greek get the [__]
out of here and let us have our
democracy Prince Phillip his dad was
like in charge Greece yeah yeah Prince
Philip was he was born in Greece I'm
Greer than yeah exactly he was born in
Corfu crazy yeah well the reason I'm
happy you bring that up is because I've
been monitoring this one like crazy
since the beginning because that
Jordanian King I first got introduced to
him through Joby War's books and I was
blown away by him he's a very sweet guy
one of the things and now I I know like
several people who are like friends with
him from different walk you know he's
got a beautiful house in DC yeah he's
got two actually he's got one in pic
Maryland that was his dad's and then
he's got a he's got a magnificent condo
in the in the uh what is it the not the
Waldo story the
um in New York Four Seasons no the in in
Georgetown okay yeah I'm less familiar
yeah but you know he the thing that blew
me away with Joby is that joby's first
book was about El belly the guy who blew
up the base the CIA base who was a
Jordanian doctor I think I'm in that
book you probably are yeah what do you
remember the context you might have been
yeah I sat next to uh Jennifer Matthews
the woman who
died yeah we were branchs together oh
yeah yeah yeah I knew her very well we
were we she was the chief
of I forget what she was the chief of
and I was the chief of Counter
Intelligence in Alex station so we sat
next to each other oh [__] mhm you were
the chief of int did you tell me this
before I don't know I don't remember you
were the chief of Counter Intelligence
on the bin Laden desk yeah for how long
oh not long uh from when I got back from
the Abu aate operation to when I went up
to the seventh floor as the uh executive
assistant okay so this is after 911
after 911 all right I think we did talk
about this well but let's take a little
side trip though we'll come back to the
king what was that like at that point
cuz he's in the weeds he's in the wind I
should say yeah he was in the wind so my
job was
to was to
counter um Al-Qaeda efforts to
infiltrate the
CIA Al-Qaeda was infiltrated was yeah
did they ever successfully do it no um
but the closest they ever came was
unfortunately the host bombing where she
was killed uh right so source
infiltration got it all right you know
may I finish a couple thoughts on
Jennifer and this I told Joby this when
he was writing the book
um many of us were furious with the CIA
not with Jennifer Jennifer [__] up and
it but it was not her
fault the cia's got this rule stupid
rule that in order to be promoted to the
senior intelligence service you have to
have done a rotation in the policy
community and a rotation in another
directorate so like for me I started in
the DI I went to the do and then I did a
a rotation to the state department where
I was in the American Embassy in Bahrain
for two years and then I was the Iraq
desk officer at State legitimate State
Department jobs so that made me eligible
to be a promoted to the senior
intelligence
service
she um had done a rotation at state
but she had never done a rotation in
Ops well post 911 everybody's like a
chicken without a head right so if
you're going to if you're an analyst a
career analyst she'd been in for you
know 12 15 years by
then
um you're an analyst and they want to
move you into an operational position
you've got to go through something
called the operations course accelerated
OCA so you skip all the CIA 101
silliness you know this is what a cable
is this is what an operation is this is
you know you already know all that stuff
so you just skip it so instead of an
18-month class yours is six months and
they teach you how to shoot and how to
do the crazy driving and how to build a
bomb and how to take a bomb apart and
how to do all these different things in
those six weeks and then you go out to
the field so all of this the weapons the
counter surveillance all this stuff is
fresh in your mind but with Jennifer
they're like oh my God we need somebody
to go to host like right now hey
Jennifer you need a rotation of the deal
right so you can get promoted okay go to
Coast can you go
tomorrow and they send her she didn't
know what the [__] she was doing she
didn't have any experience at all in
operations zero experience in operations
she was brilliant and a great analyst
but they didn't train her to protect
herself and the next thing you know we
get this volunteer and he's been Laden's
doctor and oh my God it's amazing El
belly yeah belly and so this is going to
be the greatest source we've ever had
against Al-Qaeda and it just fell into
our lap cuz he just
volunteered and let's bring him onto the
compound and then they learn well it's
his birthday right so we're going to
bake him a cake we're going to bake him
a cake and sing happy birthday oh you
know what would be a better idea let's
meet him outside the Hardline let's meet
him where we can't be protected because
that'll show him how much we like him
and how grateful we are for his
information and we'll give him the cake
so everybody leave your post and let's
all go out to the
car now as crazy as this is so far he
gets out of the car and he's muttering
to
himself and that wasn't alerting to
anybody what does that mean again in the
name of God the merciful the
compassionate there is only one God and
he is God and Muhammad is the messenger
of God yeah yeah that's not what you
want to hear when they stand there with
a [__] birthday cake no and then he
blows everybody up yeah
it was the
worst it was the
worst deadly attack in CIA history we
lost more people that day than in any
other day in the history of the CIA this
is like what like 07 MH so you were out
I was out I was at ABC news then doing
uh counterterrorism commentary got it
that's where your timeline picks up but
so you were with her though on that desk
for
yeah yeah what was that desk like busy
yeah where where what kind of leads were
you getting on them there no one knew at
that time no most of what we were
getting was [__] you know you you get
when I was in Pakistan I used to get
these people all the time um walk-ins
yep so a walk-in is somebody who
literally walks in off the street and
says I have intelligence that I want to
share with the CIA okay
98% of the time is it's a
lunatic right 1% of the time it's either
what's called an intelligence Peddler
which is somebody who actually has a
nugget of interesting information and he
brings it to you and you give him a
$100 but then he goes to the British
Embassy and then the French Embassy and
then the Russian Embassy and then that's
a month salary make a living yeah yeah
yeah legit yeah the other half percent
is what's called a probe
so this is usually usually
Iranian um it can be Hezbollah or North
Korean and they'll come into the embassy
like this they'll be like uh yeah I have
um I have uh information I want to give
to the CIA can you call a CIA guy down
here for me and they're looking like
where are the
cameras um are the doors armored are the
windows armored how many of the people
on dealing with have guns can I see the
true name of anybody on their badge or
have they obscured their badge how many
checkpoints do I have to get through
before I'm actually inside so in the
event that they want to attack our
embassy at some point and blow it up
they've got a design on how to do that
that's why we keep them outside the
Hardline only in the smallest embassies
do you bring them in but otherwise you
know I'll meet you at that Shack in the
parking lot cuz you're not coming in
here yeah but then the remaining 1% is
the real deal and the oldtimers who
worked against the Soviets will tell you
that the greatest sources in the history
of the CIA started as Watkins because
they're so deep down into the
weeds that you would never encounter
them you're not going to meet those
people at some diplomatic cocktail party
right you're not going to meet them
anywhere officially like are you going
to meet a North Korean nuclear scientist
at a cocktail party of course you're not
but he may just walk up to the Embassy
and knock on the door that's the that
that that's a career making sure uh
Recruitment and so when they saw balawi
and he's you know pretending to be well
I'm not sure I want to do this well but
maybe I should because 3,000 Americans
were killed oh my God I can't believe
I'm doing this he played it just right
yeah and they were so excited because
this was the first major source that we
had
akin to what we once had against the
Soviets this is going to make people are
going to get medals they're going to get
promoted you know this is going to be
incredible hey guys if you haven't
already subscribed please hit that
subscribe button it's a huge huge help
thank you where did you guys when you
were on the desk four whatever somewhere
in there where did you guys think he was
where was where was your inkling bin
London
y it was pretty well split I thought he
was in Afghanistan
and um I just didn't think he had the
wherewithal to get out from torab Bora I
thought that he was hunkered down in a
cave I really did and then you know
later on I said somebody said oh he's
probably still in that cave and I said
no that doesn't make sense we know that
he's got kidney problems and it's cold
in caves you can't be you can be in a
cave okay overnight but not years in a
cave I said he's probably in some little
village somewhere in some you know mud
hut and then the other half believed now
he's probably in Pakistani probably like
right on the border somewhere we didn't
realize he had gotten so far in and he's
staying at you know what was effectively
the West Point of of Pakistan crazy yeah
right on top of that's nutsy that can I
go back to John Cary whatever you want
you've just reminded me of something or
I've reminded myself of something he
asked me like I'm going to say no [__]
you one of the things I told Carrie
early on he he told me hey we need to
come up with some investigations this is
when I thought he actually meant it
before I learned better yeah and I said
um are you planning any international
travel and he said yeah I want to go to
Pakistan and Afghanistan I said okay
I'll go with you to Pakistan and
Afghanistan but I think what we should
do is the doctor that led us to Bin
Laden do you remember the story of the
doctor we recruited a Pakistani doctor
to go to abadabad let me back up so so
we've got drones and the drones are
flying over abadabad we we had a source
who said hey you know there's a guy in
abadabad and he's really tall and he
just walks in circles in the backyard
never leaves just walks in circles in
the backyard so maybe it's beenin Laden
and we said yeah maybe it is maybe it
isn't but another thing that's
interesting about this house that he's
in is most of the houses have um 8ft
tall walls around them CU you don't want
anybody to see your your women
right you put walls around your house
yeah you got to keep them protected but
this wall around this house is 20t it's
not 8T so and this guy this tall guy in
white just walking in circles [__] anaki
someone's in there right somebody this
is somebody whoever it is if it's not
bin lad it's
somebody so what we did is we recruited
a doctor and a Pakistani doctor and we
said we want you to go to abadabad go to
this neighborhood and give free polio
vaccines but as you're giving the polio
vaccine
take a little DNA
test now somewhere RFK is going this is
how they C you they come up with the
polio vac and then you're [__] got in
Laden so
um excuse me the bin Laden family was
was deeply ashamed of what Osama had
done so they offered us um
they offered
us their help and we said well what
would be nice would be would be a DNA
sample so in case we kill him and we
blast him to a million pieces we can
pick up a piece of meat and run a DNA
test and confirm that it's him that was
a nice Flex you just did by the way that
was why I laugh they showed me something
but go
ahead I thought you'd get a kick out of
it yeah I love how you just like don't
stop the story just keep going he'll
laugh so um
so we had the DNA profile of Bin the bin
Laden family in
general so we recruit this doctor he
goes in the neighborhood hey you know
playing the music no there's no music
like a ice cream ice cream truck G I
would have gone um free polio vaccines
for everybody and these women bring the
children out and he gives the polio
vaccine and he takes a little DNA we run
the sample Bin Laden
family so they had called him the
Walking Man all this time and uh it was
then that they were able to confirm it
was him so Obama sends in the the uh the
stealth helicopters they kill him they
take the body they take the wives the
rest is history so I said to Carrie this
is
2009 the pakistanis arrested that doctor
they charged him with espion say before
he's killed because he's killed in 2011
correct right yeah so I said we should
get him out and bring him back to the
United States oh cuz you knew that you
were read in on the intelligence that
they confirmed it was him you knew about
bin lad's whereabouts two years before
it happened and you weren't even in CIA
anymore yeah people talk how do you know
people talk holy [__] they get excited
and they can't keep it to themselves
yeah I'm going to tie you down later and
[__] get all the secrets out of you
I've been out 20 years now pause so um I
said to Carrie we should get this guy
out I said you'll be you'll be a
national hero if you can get this guy
out and the pakistanis loved Carrie so
he's like that's not reassuring no and
he's like now he just starts cracking
he's like I don't want to interfere in
the uh you know the internal uh
relations the internal politics of I
said I said Senator there's no there's
no downside to this there's no downside
this guy risked his life to give us
Osama Bin Laden let's just do him a
solid bring him back wouldn't do it
just wouldn't do it and did he give you
a reason he legit didn't want to get
involved and now he may have had the
idea on his own and raised it with Obama
and Obama said [__] you or he said
something to you know
whoever whoever
was CIA director at the time I don't
even oh uh it was um Hayden 09 would
have been hayen right after Hayden Morel
Morel was
acting um
no it was uh what's his face from
California the congressman uh Leon
Panetta yeah it was Leon Panetta because
then Panetta went on to be that's right
he was in charge when the B L thing
that's right that's right so maybe there
was some some component here that I
didn't know that he I already had the
idea I said to Obama and Obama said no
and Panetta said no I have no idea but I
I thought you know we should we should
help this guy out because he risked his
life for us and Carrie's just like not
interested did we ever get that guy out
so he's still getting his balls
electrocuted today that's terrible yep
he sure is wow yes he
is all right so we were talking about
alelly with this though yes because so
you this is wow what a great Rabbit Hole
so you knew all the players involved
here what was going on so you already
laid it out he went on if you saw the
movies Zero Dark 30 this scene was shown
I'm still angry about that stupid movie
why because it
it perpetuated the lie that it was the
torture program that led to Bin Laden's
location uh yeah that was a lie great
analysis led to Bin Laden's location
they kind of showed both yeah but I see
what you're saying they included that as
torture had nothing whatsoever to do
with his location nothing they recruited
the right people they used the right
technology and they found him yeah you
and I talked about this a lot last time
we here so people could check out 249
250 where we went through that so we
won't go through that again but either
way that scene was shown in that movie
and from what I understand maybe you can
give your input here it was pretty
accurate that one it was it was
generally accurate minus the torture
part no no I mean the the scene the
actual one the scene was was 100% in
fact I I talked to uh who' I talk to
Business Insider magazine couple of
weeks ago they had me review like eight
eight intelligence related movies you
did one of those it was so so much fun I
can't wait to do it again um but one of
them was that scene yeah and it was
right on Wow right on you know the only
sad part is that three different um Navy
Seals claim that they were the ones that
did the kill shot yeah there's I'm not
going to get involved with that yeah you
can go online and look there's some
interesting conversations in the Navy
SEAL Community around that one of them
has made a living off oh yeah yeah now
yeah yeah there there's I don't like
getting involved in the military drama
cuz I don't know [__] about [__] that's
Theirs to do but there are certainly
like I I think that there's one guy
we're going to have in here who I want
to talk to about it off camera because
he's had some things to say I don't want
to personally get involved but yeah I I
kind of wonder why that's not a louder
story that there's multiple like it's
talked about but there's one guy who
it's like oh yeah that's who did it and
then there's a lot of other people who
are like no the [__] he didn't no he
didn't you know there's an auction house
on Maryland's Eastern Shore Alexander
auctions they they specialize in um
military auctions and 75% of what they
auction is um is Nazi right um they even
had I they had an auction a couple weeks
ago they had Eva bronze night gown did
you go buy it like where the no it was
like
$50,000 John's like I wanted to I've fit
on a couple things but um you can't
believe the stuff that they have that's
been signed like random stuff that's
been signed by this Navy SEAL who claims
that he's the guy the one who's made a
living from it like a soccer ball signed
by the guy I don't want to say his name
and maybe he was maybe he was but is it
really worth $500 for an autographed you
know Time Magazine with Bin Laden on it
that this Navy SEAL signed I just don't
understand what because one thing about
the veteran Community is godamn are they
strong with The Stolen Valor stuff
they we've seen it in here with with
some stuff where they got it wrong and
you know ran with stuff but you know you
would think that's the that would be if
that's the case the biggest Stolen Valor
in modern history ever and you would
think there'd be a lot louder push
that's why I'm I kind of I'm kind of
like maybe he probably did Kill the guy
you know regardless of what you think
about him
because it's not loud there's some
arguments but it's not like someone
people every day like this didn't happen
yeah I don't know it's CRA I don't know
I don't know what the truth is I'm out I
don't want anything to do with it it is
one of the most one of the most
incredible and compelling and exciting
scenes that a person can imagine uhhuh
but I don't know who imagine you put
three in the head of Bin Laden can you
imagine that' be [__] awesome I would
think about it for the rest of my life I
know I wouldn't have any I mean yeah
like what how do you top that in a
career you don't no you don't I I don't
think anything's ever the same after
that no no way but so the scene of el
belly accurate you told s too yes cool
that let me add one thing about Job Joby
book uh sorry joby's book is the most
comprehensive account of what happened
that is humanly possible yep he talked
to
everybody and the way he lays it out is
very compelling and completely true so
you actually took the words out of my
mouth because that's exactly what I'm
going to refer to his book that was
published in 09 yes covered that scene
specifically and what led up to it yes
and so when he wrote this book the guy
was a Jordanian this was a very bad look
for Jordan oh boy in fact they
apologized to us yes and Joby wrote the
book like he does fairily just reporting
he's a great Storyteller but joby's not
the guy who says [__] you nothing like
that just the facts so he writes this
book and two things happen number one El
Bello's father who did not feel the way
El belloy did and was embarrassed of
what happened put the book on his mantle
because he said it was written fairly
wow or whatever that's incredible the
second thing that happened obviously
this whole thing's a very bad look for
the king and it was not written nicely
to the king you know it's reporting
things that are not good for the mukar
and obviously the things that slip
through the cracks here the king hit up
Joby and said hey you could have been an
[__] about this you could have
injected a lot of opinions in there this
is a really bad look for me but you did
this the honest way it is a bad look for
our country you know we [__] up this
this or that I appreciate the fact that
you know you did it in a professional
way so if you are ever writing a story
in the future and you need some help
getting sources you call me and I I will
do that for you which then ended up
being the book on Isis which one of the
pulit are oh my God and once again the
first chapter really bad look for the
king and the guy is still friends with
Joby and everything which tells me he
respects in some way the relationship of
you know what's supposed to be like the
fourth estate of Life yeah right and so
I have followed the guy religiously
since I read that book years ago and I
just found him so interesting so what
you know he speaks perfect English he's
perfect he's Western English is as good
as ours he's This brilliant guy he also
I like this about him never wanted to be
king never thought he was going to be no
it was supposed to be his uncle yeah and
his and then it was supposed to be his
older brother MH and his father's on his
deathbed and says no fam you're doing it
switched it up and he was like what the
[__] and then his dad died that's that
yeah it was shocking so the guy you know
he's been King now for 25 years or
whatever first of all every major event
he has been the no seramis on he playby
played how Iraq was going to happen when
he was talking with the US in 01 and 02
right like he gets so much I'm sure he's
got some shitong there but like he get a
lot right he understands the Middle East
so well and so right when October 7th
happened I was turning right to him like
all right what's this [__] gonna
say about this his wife's paladian so
he's got a little feeling there she's
stunning isn't she she is Queen Raina
right that's what it is so he was at
some conference or something this is
like two weeks after October 7th and he
gives these long comments on this and
one of the questions that he was asked
and we actually had a clip go viral
where I was explaining this last year
and a lot of people didn't know this but
one of the questions that he was asked
was will you commit to taking in
Palestinian refugees right and he said
I'm glad you asked that no I will not or
I I think they said to him why have you
said you won't do that I think it was
like a leading question because he had
said like he won't do that he said if I
do that you know because he's he has an
allyship with Israel but that doesn't
mean just like you know someone might
not like our president at a certain time
it could be the same with him so he
basically said if I did that I would be
giving the worst parts of Israel's
government the guys I don't like exactly
what they want that's a great answer the
smotes the Ben gavers and all that
because they believe in this expansion
and I would be ethnically cleansing
these people from that plot of land and
they'd never be able to go back and now
like I was telling people about this and
I felt like this was one topic on this
issue people weren't talking about a lot
and now it's being talked about all the
time because now you're seeing it play
out and there was like you know
Netanyahu two things happen Netanyahu
this is what I want you to respond to
Netanyahu comes in meets with meets with
Trump trump actually did something I
didn't expect which we'll see how this
turns out it looks like if you watch the
press conference where they did publicly
Trump shocked Netanyahu he hadn't told
him this and said the us is going to
handle it it's a very Trump thing to do
I kind of like that it's it's like a
halfway or it's like I still don't like
this but it's better am I wrong
no you're not wrong okay even Putin said
um that he he preferred Trump to Biden
because Trump was so
unpredictable you never knew when he was
going to do something or propose
something that was really
great and you just you knew not to
expect anything great from Biden but
netan who hated that when he did that
cuz he wanted it
yeah so maybe this will be a situ cuz I
haven't liked the way Trump's talked
about it after but maybe it's a
situation where the people who live
there will actually end up getting to
stay there which leads to my second
point that I don't know if you saw this
but he then had the Jordanian King in
they had a very interesting 19 and a
half minute public press conference
together Jordanian King's a real master
and handling it he is he's a master
Diplomat so he commits in that to Tak in
2,000 kids who have cancer and stuff
like that which I think that's great M
Trump liked that and Trump was kind of
dancing around the whole well are we
going to settle him permanently in
Jordan or have discussions about that
and the King was able to kind of stay
away from the melee the media kind of
kept him out of that but do you think he
will be forced to relent on something
like that no that is a red line for the
jordanians that if cross could actually
eventually lead to the collapse of the
Jordanian government like I said there
are already so many Palestinians in
Jordan that do not have full the full
rights of citizenship yeah right in fact
they have they even have different color
passports jordanians have green
passports and Palestinians in Jordan
have black passports so you can tell
when they're Palestinian and they're
second class citizens there now they
know after 70 years they're not going to
get their country back they're not going
to there's no right of return that the
Israelis are going to finally agree to
they're stuck in georia Jord and they're
pissed off for four or five generations
now and so to make that worse you
Jordanian is a country that has no money
it's one of the largest recipients of us
aid but people still live in poverty
there for the most part um to Heap on
the problems that Jordan already has
where they've got Israel and the
Palestinians on one border they've got
Iraq on another border they have Syria
on another border this is a very
dangerous neighborhood right they have
enough problems as it is they can't take
another million
Palestinians it's too much it'll tip the
balance what if the United States leans
on them to end up doing that though how
do you even say no I think they they
would have to say no because you know
how the Israelis always say you know
that it's either Victory or be pushed
into the sea right it's kind of the same
thing for the jordanians on this you
know I think I I may have told you a
story a very dear friend of mine one my
first boss at the CIA um he became the
senior director for the Middle East at
the National Security Council under
Clinton and the very last week of the
Clinton presidency he and Al Gore were
at Camp David with yaser Arafat and his
people and whoever the Israeli Prime
Minister was I forget now and his people
whether it was rabine no rabine was dead
by then yeah Dead uh Shimon Perez
probably well I would it would have been
Netanyahu noine not in 2000 January of
2000 no that no that would have been
Epstein's buddy the hell's his name it
had to be Shimon Perez right no what's
the guy's can we google
Epstein prime minister friend why the
[__] he he was in that movie they showed
up in the one scene where they where
they hit people because he used to be a
special for yeah AUD Barack was it AUD
Barack yeah yeah I guess it was yeah he
succeeded in 2000 yeah okay so he said
there there there's this enormous map of
Jerusalem on this conference room table
he said they're so close to peace
they're literally dividing Jerusalem
block by block with a sharp
E and they finish and they come to an
agreement and Al Gore says my God we
have peace and Arafat says I can never s
this to the Palestinian people and he
starts to walk out yeah and Gore runs
out after him and he said you can't just
walk out if there's something that
you're having second thoughts on tell us
we'll renegotiate it we can't come this
close to peace and just just let it uh
fall
apart and he said I could never sell any
agreement with the Israelis to the
Palestinian people and that was the end
of it this is where and this is where I
always defend Israel with this stuff
these are the realities they do face
these people will be like nowhere right
you're right and what we're talking
about here is a legitimate and viable
two-state solution yes and it was the
Palestinians that walked that's right
and that has happened again and again
that that now listen if there are a lot
of Palestinians who live there who may
not have voted for that leadership or
were pressured into voting for that
leadership I have tremendous empathy for
that I know that's a real thing totally
agree but the people who have been given
the power or taken the power to be in
charge whether it be Arafat and and the
PLO or you know what we've seen in Gaza
with [__] Hamas yeah these are not
good Representatives no you got you've
got Mahmud Abbas who's 16 years into a
four-year term as president and you've
got a a Bonafide terrorist group uh in
in Gaza so I mean what do you do now
like the Israelis I went to Israel twice
uh in 2022 for work both times it was
you know I had never been to is before
never been to 72 country r with the
agency I had never been to Israel so I
went uh as a
journalist an incredible absolutely
incredible transformative Place
beautiful place I've been it's it's the
best and the worst of what the Middle
East has to offer it's a good way to put
it and uh I mean I was
just struck by it
and the the you know I went for the for
the uh election the Israelis are adamant
about
the death of the two-state solution
right there will not be a two-state
solution well there is already the
one-state solution and that's not
working out very well is it right and I
was talking to a former Ambassador just
the other day and he said you know why
aren't we talking about the three-state
solution he said the the Gaza
Palestinians and the West Bank
Palestinians have literally nothing in
common yeah they're literally
geographically separated yeah they're
geographically separated they're even
kind of ethnically separated right the
the Gaza Palestinians have more in
common with the Egyptians than they do
with the Westbank and they don't really
like each other and politically they're
at odds yeah so he said I think we
should be having a conversation about a
three-state solution and I think he said
that a three-state solution would look
more like Bosnia heroina where you look
at the map and it's all these little
dots these little islands like here's
you know Bosnia but all these little
dots either belong to to Serbia or
Croatia it's it's like a map made of
Swiss cheese yeah but it works it works
but there's not this is the whole here's
where I'll push back on that this is the
holiest land in the world that's the
problem people get weird about it and
it's like you know this is this is where
I see it from Israel's perspective for
sure it's my my friend Eric ziger has a
great quote I say all the time you said
people are not their governments I would
never want to be [__] co-signed to
dict Cheney and George Bush and what
they did right and I understand why
other people might take the easy way out
around the world and do that at that
time you know when they were around but
you you have a lot of Israeli people who
don't support their current government
and even people that may have voted for
that because it was the least of what
they viewed as two evils they're not bad
people at all right so I'm thinking
about Israel after that government when
there's a more moderate government or
something more reasonable the the most
that Benjamin Netanyahu has ever won has
been like
27% I didn't even know that they have so
many uh political parties in that
country that they have these these um
governments that are made up of you know
a half a dozen or more different parties
yeah yeah but my issue there would be
even though the two places don't see eye
to eye I did know that I didn't know
they were like ethnically different I
got to look into that more but I I know
the two areas don't see eye to eye you
have poo and Hamas and very separate
cultures now you have have two places
that are on your borders who got a lot
of people who don't [__] like you and
it's going to create a self-fulfilling
prophecy in fact and that's the Israeli
argument and and but that's the thing
they have a good argument here when you
look at
Gaza I almost from not now but back then
I actually see it the way Netanyahu saw
it in ' 03 and bear with me
here he left the finance ministry he was
the Finance Minister he's actually a
very successful one he was good at that
job MH in protest over giving Gaza up
and he told them he warned them for you
know the two years leading up to it if
you do this I will leave and he left and
you know he was an OG on this because he
said all right you're gonna have a
border with people who [__] hate you
imagine if instead of Mexico we had Iraq
as our border in 2006 we'd have the
biggest most beautiful border wall
you've ever seen in your [__] life
yes okay but you created a 20 mile by
accident prison because North border
Israel east border Israel South border
the Sinai which is owned by Egypt a run
by terrorists who don't like the
Palestinians right West border the
[__] sea which the coral reef is
where you get all the fish is nine miles
out which is Israeli territory so
there's no [__] fish that's exactly
right right so you now you created knows
that yeah but I I've heard this before
true over the years it's true you can't
fish so how do you if if you're Israel
how how do you not create that you're
trying to throw him a bone give them
land but you then create a space where
well there was an idea that came up in
the early 1990s it was it was a Saudi
idea um the Saudi idea was to use Saudi
money to build a port and an airport so
you can close them all off you can run a
a border fence or wall you know a mile
out into the sea you can mine the area
around the Border do whatever you want
have ships off the off the coast but let
them at least trade you build them a
port so they can have have Ships coming
in with food and medicine and whatever
you know going out with whatever
products they they can make in Gaza I
have no idea you know what that could be
um and an airport that would connect
them with the rest of the world and the
Israelis said absolutely not why now
that's stupid I know why' they say no CU
they wanted it in
[Music]
1991 I think they hadn't got gotten
there yet intellectually you know what I
mean but things have become so desperate
in the intervening years I mean it's
we're talking about 34 years ago things
are so desperate now that unless you
want to just complete this genocide that
you've started you're going to have to
throw them a bone what about 05 why
didn't they bring that back up that's a
good question I don't know see that
there's not a defense for that that's
the kind of stuff there's not defense
for on on the broad basis I understand
why they're like well we can't really
let them in here you know you're letting
in it's like SSS cheese in the wrong way
yeah I get that it's just godamn that's
that's one of the most cynical
situations in the world it's awful just
awful I just don't know if it'll ever
get solved yeah I have to agree but you
guys you started to say this earlier and
it was very interesting you had a very
telling 30 to 35 minute segment with
Danny Jones and Andy boo Damonte where
the two of you who were from different
eras of CIA told the same story about
how this is behind the scenes with you
know the F the Frenemies kind of thing
that's going on you already started to
say there were red lights you know
you're told that day one it's like you
see China you see Russia you see Israel
as like spy threats or whatever that's
right so people at CIA I would
imagine have a LoveHate relationship
here is that fair to say uh it's mostly
just a hate
relationship I never met anybody at the
CIA who is pro Israel never not one not
a single person
no no not a single person and it's
because they make it so hard to like
them you know if we're supposed to be
their best friends we have this special
relationship well I I'll tell you the
same the same story I told Danny Jones I
worked with this guy for years and he
married a woman in the office really
terrific people both of them terrific
people and when I was going out to train
uh on my rotation to the state
department the wife was going out to
Jerusalem because she got the same
rotation to the state department so
because she had worked with the Israelis
for many years uh the station decided to
declare the two of them to the Israelis
so they they land and they go straight
to mosad and the chief said these are my
officers she's on rotation to the state
department and he's just going to study
Arabic at the University of Tel Aviv
yeah right no harm uhuh so they're there
for a little while they go to a party at
the ambassador's residence and they come
home and all of their living room
furniture had been rearranged and they
were like you know not cool but this is
what the Israelis do they break in the
house they rearrange all your furniture
just to say ha [__] you we can do
anything we want so they're there
working months past they're having a
good time they go to uh the ambassador's
Christmas party now they're living in
Jerusalem
the embassy at the time was in Tel Aviv
and so it's about a 30 or 40 minute
drive to get from one city to the other
they come home at the end of the party
and people had taken shits in all of
their toilets in their house every
toilet had had [__] in it you know not
cool they're not doing anything they're
not working against the Israelis they're
just doing normal stuff he studying
Arabic she's just in the the embassy's
uh you know economic section or whatever
and um and then when their tour was over
two-year tour the Ambassador threw a
going away party for them which is a
normal
thing and they get back to the house and
the dog is under the dining room table
whimpering because somebody had cut the
dog's tail off and they wrapped it with
gauze and with medical tape now why why
would you do something like that what do
you hope to gain except to make us hate
you you know if you're trying to Win
Friends and Influence People that's
really not the way you you're going to
want to go so now here are these people
who if anything were you know moderately
supportive of the Israelis who came home
only with bitterness and hatred toward
the Israelis for this harassment that
lasted for two years why why would you
do that what do you hope to
accomplish do you ever think that some
of that is people who want you to think
it's them I'm still Manning it but in a
place like Israel though there's nobody
else sophisticated enough to do
something like that that's what I would
think mhm yeah it's not it's it's not
great cuz
like again I understand where they're
coming from they want our help on stuff
but you got to actually like to hear you
talk about the five eyes earlier and
give me some surprising answers on
that there's a different way you're
talking about this one yeah and it feels
like it's their game to lose and they're
doing that because it's like they could
be like the eyes with you could be and
they're deciding to just be a pain in
the balls going go It Alone mhm how do
you see this current situation winding
like the actual Gaza issue right now not
the two-state solution that's not
winding down anytime soon but how do you
see this situation winding down I don't
think the Palestinians are going to go
anywhere I think that as as awful as
things are you got a you got a territory
with 2 million people probably a 100,000
dead the Lancet the medical journal of
the UK puts it at 100 to 180,000 dead
because we don't know how many bodies
are under the rubble yet they're just
counting people who who are still
missing it's horrible it's horrible so
you got two million
people not a single working hospital no
water no food no medication it's the
worst humanitarian disaster since the
end of the second world
war and I read an article just the other
day in the Wall Street Journal that said
that it's going to take them 40 years
just to clear out the rubble it's been
so utterly destroyed the Egyptians
aren't going to take anybody the the
jordanians aren't going to take anybody
the albanians are not going to take
anybody and the Indonesians are like
leave us out of this so those guys
aren't going anywhere they're going to
have to rebuild but at the same time you
know before the fighting
started the Israelis owed the
Palestinians 2 hours of water and 5
hours of electricity every day not not
because they didn't have the capability
to provide the the water and the
electricity just to screw them you know
so every Palestinian would fill the
bathtub up with water and they would use
that for cooking for the remainder of
the day because that's all they were
allowed yeah the Israelis are going to
have to treat the Palestinians as human
beings because they've already lost most
of the world and I can't help but think
lot of the world yeah and you know kamla
Harris's position on the Gaza warart
cost her the presidency I firmly believe
that it cost her both Michigan and
Pennsylvania she she may have won the
election if she had taken a principl
stand you know you can still be
pro-israel and be anti-genocide but
you've got to put your foot down that's
the problem though there are some people
who do not speak for all Israelis by any
stretch who just have the ility to get
reach who are making that middle ground
impossible yes I will be called names
things I said today that are perfectly
factual or we're perfectly leaving open
the possibility that it's not something
else and I'm someone who comes down the
middle on this we've gotten to the point
where if you criticize Benjamin
Netanyahu as a person or as a politician
you're branded as anti-semitic which is
[__] crazy outrageous I'll tell you
my college
roommate
um I loved the guy like a brother and
he's a very religious Jew to the point
where he's become a very prominent Rabbi
in uh in
Atlanta and he told me that um he was
having a political discussion with
somebody who didn't know him and this
person says you sound
anti-semitic and he says actually I'm
very Semitic I'm the rabbi of you know
such and taking the hat off like you see
it's like what are you talking about but
this is this is where we found
ourselves you can't
criticize anything Israeli otherwise
you're branded and that's just sick yeah
but the tide will the
unfortunately like you said people are
so sick of that from a small group of
people that they're going to ruin it for
everybody else and the tide will it's
going to change that's right which which
is kind of wild so my goal is to have in
people like you who can have who can
have some Nuance on it and some
experience with it and then also I'm
working on doing two
podcasts with some one guy that I have
to get who is extremely pro- Israel and
who I like a lot I think he makes some
amazing points and then another guy who
I would say is pretty strongly
anti-israel who I also like a lot and I
think makes some amazing points and I
would like to find some Nuance in it
because John I can tell you one thing
that's not going to happen we're not
going to make a two-state solution or
peace in the Middle East on the Julian
Dory podcast it's not going to happen
you know I'm not under that delusion so
if we're going to have any effect
whatsoever it should just be that people
get to hear the different arguments and
see that this is far more complicated
I'm gonna push back on both of those
guys I think I mentioned to you one time
I I ran into Dennis Ross who was the
special Envoy for the Arab Israeli peace
process for years across presidents uh
across uh Clinton and George W bush I
ran into him in the cafeteria at the
state department one time and we sat
together and I asked him about new ideas
and he said there are no new ideas every
idea has been thought of and it's been
dismissed by one side or the other so
we've got to get everybody to the point
where they realize that there are no new
ideas and that we go back to some of
these old ideas and start to negotiate
yeah we'll see how it goes I got to run
to the bathroom real quick John we got
to talk Russia Ukraine and some stuff on
China we put a pin in sounds good all
right we'll be right back we are back on
now John you had a CIA joke I'm D I'm
driving to this event and I'm on the way
to the event I see the sign that's
nailed to a telephone pole and it says
talking
dog I was like talking dog what could
that mean I wasn't sure talking dog for
sale I'm like okay all right I'm
interested enough I'm going to see what
this is about I knock on the door I said
the guy I saw your sign you have a
talking dog for sale he said yeah it's
around back I said can I see it he said
sure I go around back and I there's a
dog there just kind of a mut and I said
hello and the dog goes hello and I said
you do talk and he said yes I talk and I
said I've never seen a talking dog
before and he said oh I've got kind of a
long history I used to work for the CIA
I said I used us to work for the CIA I
said what did you do there he said I was
in operations I said I was in operations
too what division were you in he said I
kind of went back and forth between
divisions for example he said I went
into Kim jong-un's office and I sat
there and I listened to what they were
saying and I went back out and I told
the CIA they never suspected a dog would
understand and then I went to Bin
Laden's uh compound and I was listening
to Bin Laden what he was planning I went
back to the CIA and I told them what Bin
Laden was planning and now I can go into
any any president's office or Palace or
whatever I listen and then I come back
and report I said that's incredible so I
said the guy how much you asking for
this dog he says 20 bucks I said 20
bucks why so little he goes that dog's a
damn liar he hasn't done any of that
stuff
damn it
John damn it there was there was another
joke he told us off camera too I wish
you could tell on camera that one was
good too God damn how do I even like
transition into Ukraine after that like
so not the war where [__] a million
people have died from talking dogs to
the war all right yeah the war is not
good yeah
so another one that's like hard to talk
about with people to me it seems like
there's egg on every possible face
involved with this obviously Russia
Ukraine the people funding both the US
right I empathize of course with all the
people on the ground who are dying and
awful terrible situation obviously
Russia invaded very bad and I feel bad
for the Ukrainian people in that way it
seems like their government's kind of
left them behind yeah I would agree so
many different people so many different
governments are at fault here we really
do have to go back to the 90s you know
once the Soviet Union fell apart Boris
yelton told Bill Clinton that the
Russians were interested in joining NATO
and Clinton said I don't think that's a
very good idea and then years later uh
Putin told Obama listen we're interested
in joining NATO and Obama said yeah I
don't think that's really a very good
idea not going to happen so what they
ended up agreeing on in um in
negotiations was that NATO would not to
Russia's
borders which it immediately did right
okay Lithuania Estonia lvia
Poland uh and they took it the Russians
just took it they would protest
diplomatically and they would get the
middle finger
so they didn't trust us they didn't have
reason to trust us we promised them that
NATO would not expand to their border
NATO immediately expanded to their
border it's it's an existential threat
to the
Russians
then a pro-russian prime minister is
elected in Ukraine and in
2014 we
encouraged I'm using the word encouraged
on purpose others would say we um
implemented uh a a coup a soft coup yeah
a change of government you don't have to
call it a whatever it was can you
explain what happened there you're
talking about maidon and I'm talking
about maidon it I mean it depends really
on who you believe but there there was
this pro-russian prime minister and we
encouraged an
uprising uh to depose him he was deposed
and a pro-american prime minister took
office the Russians responded angrily as
you might expect by taking
Crimea this is actually not as big a
deal as the ukrainians might have you
believe why not because Crimea was only
a part of Ukraine since
1955 it was always a part of Russia but
it was given as a gift by the Soviet
leadership to the Ukrainian people why
did they give it to them as a gift um
for their steadfastness during the
second world war so 10 years after the
war uh it was to show the people
people's quote unquote appreciation for
those ukrainians who weren't Nazis or
Nazi sympathizers um uh and because
frankly it was the ukrainians that that
withstood the brunt of the Nazi attack
that ended with the the Battle of
Stalingrad
so it's ethnically Russian even though
it belonged to Ukraine so when they gave
it to them it's not like they said we're
going to take our people out there as
well and you guys can fill it up the
same people correct because the Soviet
Union was all one country so it was the
Ukrainian SSR the Russian SSR the kazak
SSR they were all part of the same
country Soviet Socialist Republic right
um that wasn't a problem until 2014 when
the Russians go in and say now it's
Russian again and there's nothing you
can do about
it that became a problem for the United
States we started with the sanctions and
you know the propaganda began and the
the Russians were steadfast we're not
we're not leaving we're just not going
to leave and you guys overthrew the
government of Ukraine and so shame on
you for installing this pro-american
prime minister you and I were talking
offline before we started uh the podcast
about the fact that so many Americans
either ignore or don't know that every
single year for decades the United
Nations has ranked Ukraine as one of the
most corrupt governments
on the planet right they used to report
it in the New York Times too yeah they
used to they used to until it wasn't you
know yeah politically correct I guess so
um the Russians finally had had enough
and uh three years ago they invaded and
the way they invaded was they did it
very poorly yeah in that they came in
from belus which makes belus
um a combatant it's a war crime in and
of itself to use a third party to invade
another country yeah
um the United States responded much more
quickly and much more severely than the
Russians had expected uh Sergey lavro
the so the Soviet the Russian foreign
minister said that yeah same thing said
that in the Inner Circle in Putin's
Inner Circle they were surprised at how
stinging the sanctions were they were
surprised at how quickly the US was able
to implement the sanctions now here we
are 3 years later the sanctions mean
nothing to the to the Russians of course
they would like to sell energy in
Western Europe but they've gotten around
it because what the Europeans used to
buy the Indians and the Chinese now buy
so no big deal they've survived the
sanctions just perfectly
fine um in the
meantime vadir zalinski gets him self
elected prime minister he has a
reputation as being not as corrupt as
his
predecessors and you know funny thing
about zilinsky he was a very popular TV
comedian yes he was an actor he was an
actor and he had no political experience
but people liked him because he was
funny and so he won the election and
immediately becomes a wartime prime
minister does he really talk like that
yes I am vmir delinski I don't know
there's no way right seems funny to me
yeah think it is he's like 5 foot too he
is he's a little tiny guy that's why
everybody makes fun of him where when he
wears a military uniform he's never been
in the military yeah he he didn't reach
the you have to be this tall sign yeah
exactly so the the real fight is over
something called the donbas it's
primarily the regions of donet and
luhansk um now these are this is this is
Ukrainian territory but most of the
people who live are ethnic Russians and
they speak Russian as their primary
language um I know some of some donbass
ukrainians my best friend is married to
a donbass Ukrainian and they want to be
Russians really yeah even now
MH yeah they felt left out that they
were sort of cut out of Russia when the
when they cut out the when the borders
were drawn when the Soviet Union fell
apart like Hey Hey We're Russian we're
ethnic Russian question how come we have
to be in Ukraine so it's way more recent
than Crimea even oh yeah no no no it
happened in 90 1990 yeah but Crimea was
55 you said oh yeah yeah I thought you
meant Crimea in 2014 yeah yeah yeah
you're right
so you know in the end to make a long
story
short something that many of us said
analysts observers Regional experts was
this work could go
forever
or the ukrainians can concede donbass
and Crimea and then there's going to be
peace and in the end whether they do it
of their own valtion or they do it
because they're forced to militarily
that's probably what's going to
happen Donald Trump last week said we're
gonna have peace we can do it in one
day donet and luhansk go with the
Russians crimeia go the Russians pie is
at
hand and uh zilinsky is like whoa whoa
wait a minute he's calling out Black's
Freeman again get back in
here yeah but you know I mean this is a
very Trump thing to do he sees issues in
black and white I see a deal ex it's all
it's all about a deal but he will cut
out the people that he don't that he
thinks or doesn't think want to
participate in the deal like for example
the Abraham Accords peace in our time in
the Middle East nobody told the
Palestinians it's the same thing here he
says like a couple days ago
zelinsky's approval rating is 4% no it's
actually 47% it is yeah it's not 4% it
where he get in the four he just dropped
the seven he just makes it up yeah yeah
he just makes it up four 4% uh he better
hope he makes it to the next election
well that was a that was a shot at a
comment that zalinsky made when Trump
called him a a dictator the day before
um he said I'm not a dictator and Trump
said there are no elections in Ukraine
well the answer is because the Ukrainian
Constitution says that if martial law
has been declared by the Prime Minister
and approved by the parliament all
elections are
canceled so is he a dictator kind of but
it's it's got the legality of of the
Constitution that's a real loophole
right there it's it's a loophole yeah um
I was always one of these people who
tried to be consistent in that look if
if we're going to be peace activists
right we're going to go out there saying
oh we should all be at peace and work
together and diplomacy and all this
stuff then we really have to be for
peace I was opposed to the Russian
invasion of Ukraine but I'm opposed to
the continuation of the war too enough a
million people have been killed yeah
what do you want to kill another million
and then really devastate the whole
place nobody's going to win then let's
just get this thing over with okay
you're going to take a little haircut
territorially all right you'll live
you'll survive it all right so do you
think that other people and I'm not
talking like the worst aspects of like
the military industrial complex I'm
talking reasonable people who may be
like I don't know about that do you
think see that's that's the issue right
there
the the the Washington
swells want to fight this thing to the
last man you know this bad joke that the
US wants to fight to the last Ukrainian
well that's true
all we want to do is kill Russians to to
paraphrase gust avatus back in the 1980s
all I want to do is kill Russians they
don't care how long it takes and frankly
and I don't mean to be cynical but this
is a very good War for the for the
military uh industrial conf oh of course
very good we're going to get there
people are making lots and lots of money
yes so you you really want that to go
away what are the shareholders going to
think well that's the thing
like the reasonable
people want to push back because they
feel like the precedent set of of cow to
a little bit to a guy like Putin is bad
because then where will he stop because
he is a bulldog right and then on the
other side you have exactly what you're
talking about which is you know and
there's there's two sides to this coin
too maybe correct me if I'm wrong the
one side is it is the
military-industrial complex just coming
in saying this is good for business we
can make a lot of money Black Rock can
come in and [__] clean everything up
cool everyone's happy the other side of
it
is in the cold war with like a China
forget Russia for a second their GDP is
the size of Italy no disrespect China's
GDP is creeping up right up on us we
obviously are competing on a lot of
things around the world Ukraine in that
area is a very strategic area to make
and I hate this word but to make these
words a client State well well it's the
Bread Basket of Europe it it it produces
much of Europe's uh grain and it also
has rare earth metals yeah that we would
have to either otherwise buy from the
Chinese or from the
Afghans I mean the Congo only has so
much that we that we need we got to get
the rest of it somewhere else and the
ukrainians have it and you said this is
and I've always heard this as I point
out but like this is a place that was
always called corrupt
oh my God and why did they call it
corrupt because Russia was involved in
their politics or a lot of other things
no no no it's about cash it's about it's
about money I'll give you I'll give you
a couple of examples I knew you
would so I mentioned my best friend uh
from college uh he's married to a
Ukrainian woman of Russian
extraction
and her brother still lives in Ukraine
so my buddy was doing relatively well in
life decided to help his new
brother-in-law out by going in uh with
him on an investment they bought um they
bought the first combination gas station
car wash in donbass h first one novelty
so place to launder money to well that's
a different
conversation so they buy it from this
Ukrainian guy and as soon as they
affect the deal and they pay the money
and they get the the
deed uh the guy Su them and says oh they
stole it from me I want all the money
back and he bribes a judge to rule in
his favor oh boy
so my my friend has never dealt with
anything like this before he hires an
attorney in in Kiev says what should I
do the guy's like oh we're so corrupt
here what you're going to have to do is
Sue him back and buy a judge at the next
at the appet level yeah at the appellant
level so he does he bribes this judge at
the appellant level and of course he
wins but the original owner then sued
counter sued and bought a judge in the
Supreme Court oh my God so my friend
enlists the American ambassador
and uh the Ambassador writes a letter to
the governor of the donbass and I'm sure
they all laughed at him uh and uh
because my buddy wasn't willing to Shell
out another 25 grand for the for his own
Supreme Court judge um he just let the
thing go they lost everything they had
wow second
example and this is very controversial
and it really hits me in the
gut the Ukrainian Orthodox church has
been in under the jurisdiction of the
Russian Orthodox church for a little bit
more than 1,000 years okay in the
hierarchy of the Orthodox Church there
is no difference between the Russians
and
ukrainians so Hillary Clinton when she
was the Secretary of State asked
ecumenical patriarch Bartholomew the of
Constantinople if he would declare the
Ukrainian Orthodox Church to be what's
called
ailis it runs itself no longer subject
to the whims of the Russian
patriarch and the patriarch said I'm not
sure that's a good idea they've been
under Russian jurisdiction for a
thousand years politically I really
can't do that and Hillary allegedly
said would $20 million help make the
decision well the Greek Orthodox church
is under the thumb of the Neo ottoman
Turks and so he said yeah we could use
the 20
million so she said we have to give it
to you through Ukrainian Banks that's
fine so the state department wires 20
million probably through USA ID now in
retrospect sounds about right they wire
the 20 million to some Ukrainian bank
they do whatever it is that they do
behind closed doors and Ukrainian Banks
and then they send 15 million to the
patriarch and he says wait a minute
where where did the five go this is
supposed to be 20 where' the five go and
the state department said oh well we
don't know anything about that all we
know is we paid so now you have to
declare independence for the Ukrainian
Orthodox Church which he did and it
immediately caused a near War situation
between the Russian Orthodox church and
the Ukrainian Orthodox church but even
even for religious purposes religio
religio military political however you
want to say it I just made up a word um
the entire culture is corrupt every
level of it is
corrupt so if we're sending 40 billion
this time 8 billion that time 500
million the next time another 15 billion
the next time where the heck is that
money going now it's one thing when the
Pentagon says look when we say we're
sending this money we're not actually
sending cash we're sending it in kind so
we take $40 billion we give it to northr
Grumman and lock heed Martin and then
they send weapons weapon systems planes
whatever yeah
but how did this terrorist attack take
place in Paris for
example using a
rifle that had a serial number
indicating that it was assigned to the
Ukrainian
military because they're taking the
weapons and selling them on the black
market to gangsters and mafiosi and
criminals and whatever and just
pocketing the money you know it's it's
like in Good Fellas you buy a case of
liquor goes right out the back door yeah
exactly exactly you that was in that's
crazy that was in my head while you were
saying this I'm picturing like that's it
that's
corruption yeah and I'll tell you as an
American who really does not have a dog
in this fight that's not what I hear
John oh yeah I hear you're a Russian
asset oh I've heard that yeah I've heard
that I'm a Russian ass you want to deny
that on the record yeah I'm not a
Russian ass all right good I believe no
I don't work for the Russian okay
continue um but as an American I I
resent my taxpayer money just being
squandered like that when we've got you
know Bridges here that are falling into
the rivers beneath them and our our kids
have to have bake sales to to buy school
supplies and you know we've got some of
the worst roads in the in the western
world yeah how come the Chinese can
afford all this stuff and and we can't
how come the Chinese have a bullet train
that goes 300 milph and we don't we have
we haven't replaced our our rails since
the Civil War did you know that well
they are replacing them in Hoboken right
now I'm not going to lie they've really
torn it up haven't they it's happening
wow we are they are fixing them they're
just building a new tunnel north of
Baltimore right now um the the tunnel
that they're using presently was built
just before the Civil War and they say
that they've been unable to upgrade the
Asel tracks because the tunnel is so
narrow they need a wider space so for
the first time in what
170 years we're finally going to upgrade
the train tracks that's crazy MH but
look at it this way too we spend more on
the military than the next eight largest
countries combined yeah that's not
cool I think it's I think it's way past
where needs to be and again once again I
see a middle ground here because I see
people who are like defund all this [__]
I for one will say if there's one part
of the military-industrial complex that
I like it's that we have bases all over
the world yeah I like that if we need it
the idea though that we have
to say let's hit the war button instead
of the let's hit the slow down button
and the diplomacy button is where I have
a real problem and it comes back to the
funding that you're talking about if
there's too much of it where you know we
can't even track this stuff the [__]
Pentagon hasn't passed an audit since
the Vietnam War ended you know that's
that's an issue you're absolutely right
you know year after year after year
Congress appropriates more money for the
Pentagon budget than the Pentagon asks
for like we want to we want 750 billion
dollar no we're going to give you 850
million dollar you get a car you get a
car exactly you get a car thank you
Oprah that's exactly right and then we
can't understand why the Pentagon can't
pass an audit you know they had price
waterhous Coopers there two years ago
they did a two-year audit and then they
just walked away they said we can't
figure this
out we can't figure this out there's no
excuse for
that no there's not there's not but
we've been fting now we we're literally
recording just past exactly three years
MH into this war because we're going to
put this episode out literally right
away next couple days but you
know the the
funding I can see where you want to take
advantage of the opportunity I draw the
line at we're at a million lives and and
like no offense the fact that
zinski thinks that this is his decision
to make is [__] insane because my
money bought bought something and it
bought our right to make the [__]
decision 100% you are right we should
get a say you know I I I I made kind of
say we need to make the decision I made
a joke when we first started uh talking
today um that you know this Lefty is
becoming a Donald Trump True Believer uh
Trump just said the war's going to end
period like it or lump it the war's
going to end make make whatever plans
you need to make and he's exactly right
and I'll tell you where he really won me
he won me yesterday and I didn't it was
just such a crazy push notification on
my phone that I saw I didn't believe it
um he's going to cut the Pentagon budget
by 8% a year for the next five years
show me one Democrat who's ever even
even proposed such a cut well they used
to it's come full circle in the olden
days of of the 60s and 70s it's come
full circle circle where there are
liberal ideas that now comb that that
are now like opted by the right and the
left's like no we've seen yeah I
mentioned this on a podcast the other
day when I was in college in history
class we studied what was then called
The Watershed election of 1932 1932 was
a historic election in American potic
politics Roosevelt um because the
Republican party was the Liberal Party
it was the party of the north it was the
the party of Labor and it was the
Democrats that were the conservative
Southern party the
slaveholders and they switched sides in
the election of
1932 um Franklin Roosevelt had been a
republican he had been the governor of
New York he had been the secretary of
the Navy um and he was a republican of
course his cousin Teddy Roosevelt was
also a
republican
so he
was economically a republican but the
Republicans had led the country to the
Great depression and so Roosevelt
decided to run for president as a
Democrat he was Democratic governor he
decided to run as a a Democrat but to
adopt a lot of the Republican party's
policies especially on labor right and
on poverty and so that election of 1932
caused the two parties to switch sides
ideologically so we studied that for
decades here we are
my position is between 2016 and 2024
we've seen a slow motion Watershed led
by Donald Trump where the parties are
switching sides again maybe not all the
way all the way like we saw in 32 yeah
but it's the Republicans who are the the
anti-war party for example it's the
Republicans who are the labor party
listen when 67% of organized labor
families Union families vote Republican
that's nuts that's pretty nuts I mean
Reagan wished he had numbers like that
and he won a majority not like Trump did
not like that so couple that with the
fact that the Democrats just have no
idea what they're doing right now it's
just a state of chaos over there at the
DNC we don't even know who the
Democratic party's leaders are right now
there are four or five people who claim
to be the leaders of the democratic
party are they really you know it it's
it's a handful of things M it's so F
this is why I feel like it's a uni party
system because if you gave anyone with a
normal head the power to go like run the
DNC tomorrow they they could win over
the country immediately yeah cut the W
[__] cut the trans [__] cut the vacine
[__] cut the [__] don't look at the
border [__] cut the endless war [__]
which I will correct one thing there is
still a contingent in the Republican
party that does
yeah and they came out they reared their
heads this week yes and then there I
forget what the sixth one is there's one
more I have in there somewhere but these
these are very common sense type things
by the way stances that like Obama had
10 years ago yes you know and they don't
do that and what's now now it's like
people are so pissed off about it that I
see the hard whipsaw back and that could
have some reverberations that people
including myself aren't going to like
and it's just the equal but opposite
action physics law of life like this is
what happens when you go too far with
stupid [__] people are going to see
through it so true you know when I see
someone with a Ukraine flag in their bio
I you know I can go through their next
[__] 40 policies word for word and
they probably don't even know what these
policies mean but that's what they were
told to do absolutely right and you know
when when you see on the Evening News
Hillary Clinton literally
kneeling in front of Henry Kissinger
that's not a brag no Henry kissen is a
war criminal yeah um when you see KLA
Harris championing and announcing her
endorsement by Dick Cheney that is not a
brag you forgot the IRS too and the IRS
and Diddy clients all the same week
Trifecta yeah seriously seriously so you
know I I I came I came from a democratic
family my grandfather had a a framed
picture of Franklin Roosevelt on top of
the TV all the years I was growing up
until he died I still have the picture I
was a third generation Democrat and I
quit the Democrats in in 2012 I'm like I
I can't do this anymore I agree with you
that on most issues we've got a unip
party two sides the same coin you can
sort of Tinker around the edges with
some differences but for the most part
they're the same that's they're getting
farther apart now oh let me correct that
because I explained that wrong then I'm
not saying they're the same in what they
say verbally no no I agree what I'm
saying is the reason reason I think
there's a unip party is because these
people openly endorse the five or six
dances I just gave and they know it's
[__] sure so why are and they know
it's against the polls so why are they
doing it sure it's the same thing with
Israel yeah they'll tell you privately
oh my God what's happening in Gaza oh my
God all these 100,000 people they're
almost all women and children oh my God
how's this happening how's it
happening you gave Benjamin Netanyahu
186 standing ovations in his last two
speeches it was four times more per
second than Kim
Yun or something like that pull that can
we get that stat yeah outrageous it's
crazy it is it's crazy and you know
another thing is corruption with the
Democrats I use this example all the
time I'm going to use it again how in
the world can Bernie Sanders win 60% to
Hillary Clinton's 40% in the West
Virginia caucus and the Wyoming caucus
and Bernie Sanders doesn't win a single
delegate Hillary Clinton wins every
single delegate yeah what H how was that
democracy he got [__] twice and he
took it which really made me angry yes
he took it cuz like you know I disagree
he obviously has some extreme policies
I'm not where he is for sure but like I
respected him as a guy who he had his
finger on the pulse he knew where the
problems were with with the average
American like he he and Donald Trump
simultaneously in 2015 2016 understood
that and it's like I think he still
understands a lot of those things yeah
but he won't you know this is a guy
who's been listed as independent for so
many years too like most of his life but
it's like something stopping him from
saying the quiet part out loud what is
that when I worked uh in the Senate
Foreign Relations
Committee I had this uh routine I I I'm
an early riser so I get to the office
early I put on a pot of coffee and then
I would go downstairs to the Senate
cafeteria to get a bagel and every
single day there's Bernie Sanders
sitting in the very first table inviting
inviting anybody who wants to sit to sit
talk about any issue they want to talk
about didn't even care if you were from
Vermont or not and the only thing he
insisted on was that you call him Bernie
I love that I loved it too and
then you know you know that old phrase
from uh Animal House uh thank you sir
may I have
another Well it's like that's what he
said to the DNC yeah here let's give you
a whack across the ass thank you sir may
I have another something else is there
something's going on something else is
there because like I don't he to his
credit he still when the when the DNC
ran comma and they were embarrassed by
that they ran from public a lot of you
know non-mainstream media they're like
let's not do it and it cost him the
election he's the one guy who didn't he
still went on these shows while this was
all going on gave his like and I respect
that but it's like what's the other part
you know people ask me all the time who
I like for uh 2028 and the answer is
nobody yeah I don't like anybody join
the club yeah I hate to say that but I
really don't like anybody everyone's
bought by somebody it's just how it is
oh I'll tell you who's the worst the
worst offender who's the worst it's got
to be John fedman
I'll tell you I I I was a True Believer
in Federman because he's from bradock
Pennsylvania I'm from Newcastle
Pennsylvania they're very close I know
where you're going with this John and
and he you know I hate the I hate the
shorts and the and the sweatshirts like
dude have some dignity and put on a
freaking tie when you go on to the floor
of the Senate the the most important
deliberative body in the world have some
respect anyway I sent $50 which was a
lot of money to me cuz you know I I
don't have $50 I have five kids I'm
still fighting legal issues I sent him
$50 and it's like he became a neocon as
soon as he got elected and I take my son
to this Ohio State Michigan State
football game last winter and he says to
me is that John fedman sitting down
there it's like 15 rows in front of us I
said I think it is John F unmistakable
so I shout fedman hey fedman and he
turns around and he doesn't see me but
he's like waving like this and I said I
want my 50 bucks back you coward and he
just waving and then he turns around and
sits down again my son's like you send
him 50 bucks I said yeah I thought he
was a lefty and he's not he's a fake
just like everybody else in the
Democratic party he got bought on some
issues he sure did yeah I remember not
too long ago they were calling him you
know Jelly Brain and all kinds of
terrible things cuz he had a stroke and
he couldn't get a word out and he got
killed in the debate because he got
confused and from his
TBI and then no I will die for Israel I
will stand with Benjamin Netanyahu it's
like I want my 50 bucks back you liar I
hear stuff like that and I'm like that's
not natural it's not because it just it
like I'm sure he was somewhat of a
supporter but it got strong like there
was like overnight and like wait a
minute off the charts and then he meets
with Trump and he's like Mr President
keep up your support of Israel our
Israeli friends need you it's like are
you kidding me it's just strange who are
you it's strange man and like and and
the thing that sucks is like not just
the the Israelis but like I have Jewish
friends who like people ask them about
this and I'm like the [__] do I know I
don't support this [__] you know but we
your Society is now turning in on itself
and this is one of the thing and I worry
about this all the time this is one of
those things because of what some of
these guys are doing and then what some
of our idiots say about
it I just look I am cynical on this I've
never had a politician at the national
level on this show one time I had a
woman on who was running for Attorney
General of a state but it was never
discussed she was not on about that no
one knows that that was the case and she
didn't bring it she's awesome she didn't
bring it up at all all you know it's
probably why she lost because she's
maybe not a full-blown politician like
the rest of them right but you know I've
always stayed away from it because
cynically I'm like who wants that job MH
who are the people who want to be in
that role especially at this point in
our history and the way these people act
what they do they cute little club that
you know a lot better than me down in DC
this is what I tried to touch on earlier
too in the 70s and even the 80s there
were some giant on Capitol Hill true
independent thinkers true intellectuals
Daniel Patrick moan you know Barry
Goldwater Ted Kennedy both parties and
now they're all midgets all of
them yeah and it's like you go on
ops.com and you can see all the
different companies paying them laid out
in black and white it's crazy mhm like
even with some of the UFO stuff like the
like the Reps who were blocking it
blocking like the Schumer Amendment and
whatever were the guys who represent
where rright Patterson Air Force Base is
and I forget what the other one is but
the one down in Alabama and it's like
yeah no [__] they're blocking this like
look at who's you know what I mean like
come on like there should be some sort
of rule like all right we're going to
vote on x today if you are funded by
anyone that has to do with X you cannot
vote on this yeah and then they all sit
down and no one would vote there was a
scene in the in the uh Simpsons movie
where uh Congress is going to vote on um
on the bill to save Springfield right
and just as they're going to vote a
congressman stands up he says Mr Speaker
I want to add an amendment uh to uh
appropriate $5 million for the perverted
arts and so the speaker says okay all
those in favor of the save Springfield
fund the perverted Arts Bill say I the
Nays have it the Bill loses that's
Congress today yeah I was on a I was on
a UFO podcast yesterday oh you were and
what podcast um a guy named uh
Chris
Chris I'm gonna find it we're gonna get
it yeah he's a good guy
um uh let's see he's a former F-16 pilot
and that's how I saved it in my oh is he
the Air Force paranormal Chris yes is
that it yeah yeah yeah I've seen him on
Twitter nice guy so we were talking
about this and he said essentially the
same thing that you know just as it
looks like this information's going to
be released somebody kills it and he
said I said well what about these what
about these videos that came out two
years ago he said no all of those were
leaked none of those were part of the
release there were documents that
released but none of the videos were
released somebody just proactively
leaked them yeah
you never saw any of that stuff when you
were back in CIA did you no were you
curious about it I I asked about it and
who' you ask I asked my boss and he said
oh he said that's the first question
that all of us have when we get here and
he said I'll tell you what they told me
when I got here oh no all that shit's at
the Pentagon we don't have anything to
do with it I don't know I'll tell you
man I saw something when I was young
that I'll never forget what was that my
my mom and dad bought a restaurant in uh
in Sharon Pennsylvania now I grew up in
Newcastle Pennsylvania it's about 20
miles away 15 miles away but to get from
Newcastle to Sharon you have to go
through Amish country and it's very very
dark because there's no electricity the
Amish live without
electricity so my dad and I worked
midnight shift on Fridays and Saturdays
so we'd leave the house around 10:00 get
there at 10:30 start working 11: 11 to 7
and we're driving through Amish Country
just the two of us and there's this
brilliant flash of white light we both
looked up and then there's a second
Flash and then a third Flash and then
this
trapezoid lights up it's got these
bright orange lights in the four corners
bright enough that it illuminated the
whole thing whatever it
was my dad pulls over he's like what is
that I don't know we get out we're
looking at it this guy pulls up behind
us gets out of his car he's like what is
that thing and we're like we don't know
and it's just hovering there and it's
completely silent so as we're looking at
it and this lasted I'm going to say this
lasted a good 10 seconds and then it
goes like that in at this fantastic
speed that I've never seen before since
and then it was
gone we get back in the car we start
driving to Sharon I said to my dad
should we call somebody should we like
call the cops or something I was 17 at
the time and he says and tell him what
we saw a flying saucer and then it flew
away yeah people are going to think
we're nuts and so we didn't tell anybody
I told my mom the next day and my dad's
like yeah it's true that's what we saw
you think that was a DARPA weapon it
could have been yeah that's my ankling
on a lot of this stuff you know at at
first people said like my
friends that first they want to know if
I had been drinking which we did a lot
of back in the day I said no I wasn't
drinking I was with my
dad they said what had to be it had to
be a balloon right and I said well
that's what I that's what I would have
thought except this fantastic speed that
it took off with I've never seen
anything like it from a standstill
making no sound just like that it was
gone so I said I I don't know what the
heck it was I'm not saying it was Little
Green Men I honestly don't know what it
was it very well could have been some
DARPA thing I mean we don't have any
military bases in the area but who knows
I don't know did you ever have any look
through or not even look through but did
did things that were happening at DARPA
ever come up in any of the work you did
yeah uh only
peripherally there was there was a point
at the end of the first golf War where I
had to get a q clearance which is a
which is a nuclear clearance they're
very tightly held uh you get a q
clearance and it's only good for like a
week or two weeks and it's only because
you absolutely positively need need to
have this classified nuclear information
so I got this Q clearance and I uh they
sent me out to vandenbberg Air Force
Base in Loke
California and
so I was able to participate in
this
meeting seminar kind kind of thing about
Advanced
Weaponry uh and it was because I had
covered the Iraqi experimental weapons
program and the guy who was in charge of
it so there were some DARPA people there
they weren't they weren't very open with
what they were doing they spoke in
generalities even though everybody was
cleared and we were all cleared for
Q um but I remember that was the first
time I had ever heard of DARPA I had
been at the agency for a year and a half
you never heard of it before n never I
had never heard of it and I went back
and I there was another guy in my Branch
who had had AQ clearance he's now like
one of the top six people in the CIA and
I
said I said have you ever heard of this
DARPA and he's like oh yeah DARPA
they're they're working 20 years in
advance yeah they're way ahead of
anything that you and I can even think
of right now I've heard 30 to 50 from
people before that wouldn't surprise me
that wouldn't surprise me yeah they and
it's funny too they've they've got these
little nondescript buildings all over
the Washington area there are no signs
or anything like there's no sign that
says DARPA headquarters right there
everywhere there's a in in Rosland uh
the Rosland neighborhood of Arlington
Virginia near my house there's a a kind
of an ugly 60s office building and um
it's across the street from a a burrito
place and a Starbucks and there's a
little historical marker in front of it
and it says in the historical marker
that this is uh this was the
headquarters of DARPA says what DARPA
was in the 1970s and it was in this
building that the internet was
invented yeah in the 70s yeah maybe
earlier they're just telling you the 70s
I mean because you know well the first
the first internet like thing that they
came up with was like 58 it was early
early what happened there I don't know
about that it was just the very first
programs they thought yeah you know
maybe this computer can talk to that
computer let's try to figure that out
but it wasn't it wasn't ready for any
kind of implementation until the
70s and then it went public you know
what 88 '89 yeah if that M crazy yeah I
just wonder about the [__] that they got
there and like yeah I think a lot of the
I think a lot of the UFO stuff is
related to that and it's and it's
protecting that and I understand that
and I say I hope we're the only ones who
are 30 50
ahead maybe we're in a situation where
China's you know so far behind in the
race that they actually think they're
winning and that's the goal here if so
you know touche they're doing a nice job
with with the disinfo but it's hard
to it's hard to judge it all in here
because I'm a podcaster in a studio in
Jersey you know like I'm not sitting in
these back rooms you got to do your best
to just sit across from the guys and
wonder what's [__] and what's not
yeah you know yeah even even with pretty
much anyone but when it gets to the
weird [__] like that you know but to to
go back to Ukraine one of the things
that like I remember when this war broke
out I did some content with my friend
David sder who is that was episode 92
and then I had him in again for episode
133 and he he was effectively the
preeminent biographer and psychologist
in the Western World on Vladimir Putin
he was assigned the bureau chief in
Moscow for the financial times in 1976
wow he was kicked out of the Soviet
Union towards the end of the 80s still
reported on Russia they had after it
flipped over to Russia they he was like
the last one to be let back in and then
I'm sure this has changed now I don't
know for a fact but I'm sure this has
changed now since the war broke out but
prior to the war breaking out he is the
only Western journalist who was ever
kicked out of Russia so Putin kicked him
out in December 2013 he was in Ukraine
headed back into Russia where he lived
most of the time and the FSB said
there's like a famous phrase I forget
what it is and they're like you can't
come back in Putin said no so you know
it was because he reported on on the on
the the bombings of of the apartment
buildings in 1999 it was him and then
the other guy who got whacked in uh in
Britain what the hell was his name lit
bko he was the FSB Insider guy they were
the only two and he was the only one in
the Western World reporting on on this
so I say all this because you know the
thing that gets lost in all the
unfortunate stuff around Ukraine and
like the corruption is that like I've
always been on Team Putin's not a good
guy you know and the [__] he does is
crazy this is a guy who's held on to
power for Now 26 years he's Rewritten
the Constitution a few times to do it he
kills anyone that's a problem he created
an oligopoly that's effectively like a
different type of Soviet Republic
afterwards and you know he kills
journalists he kicks out voices that he
doesn't like he killed his own people to
stay in power and I really David's
reporting on that is incredible I I
highly recommend people go check it out
so when David talks about this war like
he's so team ukraini and I get it
because he's lived in the middle of it
this guy's killed his friends yes but
like there still has to be the balance
here between yes Putin's a bad guy yes
Putin does all this bad [__] yes NATO's
right to push back against that but
maybe NATO takes it too far that it
causes a bad guy to be like do bad guy
[__] you know what I mean is that's my
position yeah that I think that's very
fair that's my position I agree Putin's
a bad guy always has been I wouldn't
trust any Former Intelligence officer
with running a country in any
country um I wouldn't want the CIA
director to be my president not a chance
uh but the United States does sometimes
push too hard you know I saw um uh
Richard Blumenthal this morning mhm
Senator Richard Blumenthal of
Connecticut uh complaining on CNN that
that Russia um has invaded Ukraine
Russia has invaded Georgia Russia has
invaded Afghanistan and I was like buddy
don't you read the New York Times what
about Iraq Afghanistan
Somalia Libya what do you think we do
all the
time I agree he's a bad guy yeah but
sometimes we do bad [__] that push him
to do bad things but in in our defense
on those
are is the objective supposed to be that
we then own the land and call it USA
versus this is literally on his border
and he wants to take Ukraine and make it
a part of Russia that is a difference no
yeah sure there's a difference but if we
put it into perspective if the
Canadians you know occupied something
that we genuinely thought was our
believed was ours and and its residents
said oh my God we wish we were Americans
it gets interesting
yeah yeah it does get interesting it's
it's one of those things it's like there
not really a great solution but I hope
it is more towards like what Trump's
saying which is like let's get this a
[__] over get it over with it's costing
us a fortune and a million people have
died already let's be done with it you
know I mentioned to you in the last time
in the last podcast that we did that at
the CIA we used to we used to criticize
the George W Bush Administration we used
to to criticize the bush State
Department specifically because we would
say that we had never seen a state
department work so hard to not talk to
people right diplomacy was forbidden
we're not going to talk to the Iraqis
we're not going to talk to the syrians
we're not going to talk to the libyans
we're not going to talk to the Afghans
who are we going to talk to right I mean
isn't it your job yeah to be talking to
these people to try to diffuse uh
powderkeg
situations Joe Biden was exactly the
same way we don't talk to the Russians
we don't talk to the Chinese we don't
talk to the Iranians we don't talk to
the Cubans you're showing your hand when
you do that right I suppose I'm I'm an
equal an equal opportunity hater people
say yeah yeah but if we're going to if
if we're serious about peace then we
need to have a robust and healthy State
Department that's engaging our
adversaries in in
diplomacy you know I was on I was on
this uh Iranian uh news show a couple
dayso damn John you're hitting all the
ones that are giving you a bad name I
talked to everybody because I hope I can
help to to explain some things and and
talk sense to people and I said the same
thing but I I told them listen you guys
are just as bad you don't want to talk
to us and so we end up having
confrontations in the Persian Gulf we
have confrontations at the United
Nations we have confrontations in in
Lebanon or in Yemen we have certainly
military uh confrontations in Iraq
because we won't talk to each other
that's what we should be doing talking
to each other do you think talking to
each other would stop them though from
because like this is one place I'm going
to see it from Israel for sure like they
do fun Hezbollah sure they they do Fun
open about it yes right like do you
think that would stop if we talk with
them no I don't but maybe talking could
lead to real dialogue which then could
lead to something that we could
negotiate perhaps like a talking with
kimun kind of thing where you just keep
his hand off the button
mhm do you think do you think
Iran do you think we're trying to
overthrow the Iranian regime right now I
do actively yes you think we got people
in there no but the Israelis sure do I
know
that they probably got the third ranking
[__] person in the government they
probably do yeah the Saudi um the Saudi
uh Crown Prince Muhammad bin Salman just
two or three days ago uh offered to
mediate between the White House and uh
and the Iranians which is great because
president
pesan has said publicly that he's
willing to talk to the Americans but
kamay has said he is not and he's the
supreme leader yeah so presidents come
and go in Iran just like they come and
go in the United States it all depends
on what the supreme leader says why is
NBS offering that though when when when
Saudi and Iran have been engaged in
literally literally like a hot war in
Yemen oh and elsewhere you this is a
very MBS thing to
do nobody hated the Iranians as much as
the Saudis yeah now maybe the bahrainis
too but the bahrain's pretty much a a
vassel state of Saudi Arabia I love when
you say B bahin bahin Al bahin means the
land of the two Seas um
so the Saudis and Iranians hate each
other and the Saudis
were reasonably petrified of the
Iranians Iran the population of Iran
would dwarf the population of Saudi
Arabia the Iranian military is always a
threat even if it's old even if it lacks
spare parts just the sheer number of
people in the Iranian military and the
Iranians have a pretty decent Navy so
the Saudis have been petrified of Iran
this goes back
decades and MBS when he became Crown
Prince for better for worse
said you know why don't we just make
peace with the Iranians and then we
won't have to worry about
them and that's that's what he's done
and now they've exchanged ambassadors
and pesan went to Riyad and MBs is going
to go to Teran and now they have
cultural exchanges and you can travel
freely back and forth between the two
countries and they're not worried about
the Iranians anymore like at all though
it well no they'll they'll always be
they'll always be a little bit reserved
and this is why the SA have long sought
nuclear technology um since the 80s
they've been seeking nuclear technology
just in case they need to to protect
themselves against the nuclear
Iran um but now they're in a position
where their relations with the Iranians
are good enough that they can offer up
mediation with the United States I can't
believe the Saudis don't have nukes all
that
money I would not be surprised if the
Saudis had nukes right um they they
don't necessarily have a delivery system
but I would not be surprised if they had
nukes we know that they've been seeking
nukes since the80s we know that they've
spoken to the pakistanis about it and
the pakistanis are joined at the hip
with the uh Saudis to the point where
the Saudis have been so generous with
the pakistanis that they named the city
of fisel Abad fisel Abad after King
fisel because he gave them so much money
they love love love the Saudis in
Pakistan and the Saudis see them as you
know you Pat them on head and tell him
to clean the kitchen good boy yeah
exactly
exactly so you know it's been worse
between them certainly I read a book
last year and I forget the name of it
right now on Muhammad bin salambo was
really good I want to shout those can we
google books on NBS I'll be able to see
the cover and know it Alie but about
like his rise and the [__] he does and
like I was I've long been very familiar
with the kogi story and what he did
there I mean he's not a good guy no he's
not he's murderous yeah but
we seem to be somewhat cool with him now
we are yeah why Joe Biden made a couple
of major errors in relations with the
Saudis uh MBS had ordered the the
assassination of Jamal
Kashi and they didn't just assassinate
him they did it in the most brutal
freaking fashion while he probably
watched on the screen mhm
I think I think he probably did yeah but
there there were people in the Saudi
Consulate in uh in Istanbul who could
hear him screaming as they were chopping
him up and then they never found the
body they think that the Saudi
intelligence service
probably put the pieces of his body in
separate bags and threw them in the
trash or threw them down wells in uh in
IST well they have video of them
carrying bags out too and it could have
been pieces of it I think probably was
yeah so Joe Biden said he's a murderer
he's no good you know any insult you
could think of during the the campaign
in 2020 Biden lobbed it at NBS and then
he won and then oil prices went up and
then he had to go hat in hand and I went
to Saudi Arabia for his for for Biden's
uh meeting with NBS I went to cover it I
was working for Sputnik at the time so I
went to cover I and I got in the meeting
and everything and I'll tell you one of
the things I reported I'm very proud of
this um so they're in the Royal modulus
right the this gigantic room where
everybody's sitting in a semicircle and
those of us in the media are standing
against the back wall here so the king's
in the middle next to Biden and then
it's like the foreign minister the
Ambassador the deputy foreign minister
this guy that guy Hangers On and MBs is
all the way over here on the side and I
noticed that the King has an iPad on his
lap it's discreet but he's got this iPad
and he keeps looking down at the iPad
and I thought that's kind of funny what
the heck could he be looking at on an
iPad while he's talking to the president
and then I happen to look over at NBS
and he's got an iPad and he's typing his
father messages yeah and then his father
would look down because his father's
demented MH he would look down and just
read what NBS told him to say you know
it was MBS that was running the meeting
are you like looking around like is
anyone else seeing this I know right so
I reported it that night like I can't be
the first person that's ever seen this
and then a buddy of mine at the agency
called me cuz he had seen the report and
he said you saw the iPad huh and I said
I did how long's been that has that been
going on he said since the beginning
yeah I don't even think the king
realizes he's the king yeah yeah I
believe that I mean the whole thing
about what he did with the with the Ritz
Carlton Hotel right my ex-wife was in
the Ritz Carlton then she happened to be
there during the coup your CIA ex-wife
yeah well no she's former CIA she's uh
she's a with some defense contractor
I'll bet yeah well take that for what
it's worth but uh you're not allowed to
talk about I'm not allowed to talk about
her so she happened to be in the hotel
when the coup took place and they moved
everybody to the Four
Seasons yeah
everybody and that was he basically went
after because it's exensive royal family
he made it he arrested all of his
cousins who could possibly pose a threat
to him beginning with Muhammad bin naif
this was important because Muhammad bin
naif was the Golden Boy of the Saudi
royal family why was he the gold Bo
genuinely good guy smart educated I
think it was Georgetown I can't recall
now I think he went to Georgetown but
anyway he was the head of the uh Saudi
intelligence service and nobody worked
as closely with the American government
as Muhammad bin naif he was the son of
Prince naif
naif for decades was the minister of
interior and then he became the Crown
Prince did naif become
king
no naif died before he could become king
to the best I think that's right I'm
trying to remember is that right it went
through yeah he died as Crown Prince
this guy is alive oh no oh yeah Muhammad
Ben I have alive he's in jail but he's
still in jail yeah but uh his father
uh was I forget what he was yeah put put
naif bin abdulaziz there he is yeah
until his death in June 2012 yeah he was
the uh he was the Crown Prince he died
as Crown Prince yeah and um so when he
died
um uh Salan became king well Crown
Prince no Salon the father became King
right became King right so
the Saudis had this really [__] up
kind of uh succession so the founder of
the country was king
abdulaziz um they called him iban sa the
father of Saudi Arabia um it's blood and
oil by the way alessie that was the name
of the book I just want to give those
guys a shout out was two authors cool
yeah that one right there Bradley hope
and Justin schneck great book excent
sorry go ahead so so there was no
succession plan when the old man died
but he had like 115
Sons
so king um
saoud was his eldest son king saoud
became king but he had mental problems
and so he was overthrown by his
brothers and exiled to Egypt and then um
fil became king and then fil was a
assassinated by a deranged cousin and
so Khaled became king and then after
Khaled died Fahad became king after
Fahad then came Abdullah after Abdullah
came uh Su Sultan died before he became
king and then naif died anyway and then
uh Salon became king So for years Saudi
Watchers were saying well they're going
to run out of Brothers sooner or later
right you can't just keep doing is
brother to brother it's got to be father
to son at some point so that point came
when Muhammad bin naif was named Crown
Prince people were like okay it's the
Next Generation Now is is going to take
uh Power Muhammad BF is the best
possible choice in the west we love him
he's smart he's shrewd he was the head
of the Saudi intelligence service and
and he went to Georgetown
pretty sure it was George conspiracy
brands are tingling go
ahead he had a weekly magist do you know
what a mudas is they call it a diania in
Kuwait but all the other Arab countries
call it a mudless where you have sort of
an open an open house let's call it an
open house okay so if I'm let's say I'm
I'm a young Saudi guy and I'm gonna get
married I don't really have very much
money because I'm not a royal family
member so I go to the mulus and I say
your highness you kiss him on the hand
and on the shoulder to show you're filty
um your your highness I'm I'm getting
married I'm a member of this family I'm
a member of this tribe I'm getting
married I don't have any money will you
please buy my living room
furniture and he'll say yes of course uh
Muhammad talk to this guy and get him
living room furniture the next guy comes
up oh your highness thank you for seeing
me my car broke down and I'm a taxi
driver and I need a new car uh Abdullah
give this guy a new car that's a modulus
in Saudi Arabia I got to go to one of
those [__] well there's a guy waiting
patiently in
line unbeknownst to Muhammad BF or
anybody else he had a bomb stuffed up
his
ass literally he stuffed the whole bomb
up his
ass and when he gets to the front of the
line he detonates it oh my God he blows
himself to a thousand pieces but he
almost kills Muhammad bin nav oh he
shoved it up his ass and didn't even get
to kill the guy tough way to go he
should have grabbed on to him yeah you
know like they did with Gandhi but
anyway that's a whole different thing um
ch's like good kill good kill yeah good
clean kill um
so it made him a hero in Saudi Arabia
the guy was Al-Qaeda he had come from
Yemen they had been planning this for
months the bomb was specifically
designed to go up the guy's ass it was
incredible with craftsmanship and it was
oh my God they can't believe he survived
so the Saudi people are like oh my God
and then he gets named Crown Prince they
said oh he's going to be the greatest
everybody loves him he's a national hero
this CIA invites him to the headquarters
to give him the highest medal anybody
can get because he survived this this
attack from Al-Qaeda then he goes back
and he becomes Crown
Prince and then he gets overthrown by
Muhammad B Salman and not just
overthrown but placed under arrest yeah
and then there were several other
cousins that were like hey wait a minute
Muhammad bin Salman you can't do this
we're with Muhammad bin naif well one of
them dies in an airplane crash a couple
days later the other one dies in a
mysterious one car accident on the Riad
to to jeda Highway and now there's
nobody that can challenge MBS how did a
guy that young with that many other
players who could be lined up against
him including a dude who's like an Char
of the intelligence service successfully
get everyone on his side through fear is
really what it came down to when it when
it became clear in those early days that
he was willing to kill his own cousins
just because they might someday pose a
challenge to him yeah everybody backed
off um there's a a famous Prince um uh
Al bin talal uh famous at least in the
United States because he owns a a
quarter of City Bank and he owns you
know half of uh of Berkshire hathway and
guys's a billionaire more than most
people can count um he happened to be in
Riyad when the coup took place and he
was close to Muhammad been been
naif and so they grabbed him too and
they said you could be executed as a
western spy you can be
executed uh as a supporter of Muhammad
bin naif or you can give us half of your
money and he gave him half their money
you bet he did and then he ran back to
the United States as quickly as he
could that is it's a whole it's like the
Hunger Games over there that's exactly
what it's like it's [__] crazy and
yet they have so much economic power MH
see nobody expected there to be this
kind of a psychopath in the Saudi
line of succession why not and well
because the Saudis historically have
been very very consultative they were
famous for this where it's actually
written down in a family agreement where
where and they have a name for it and
the Name Escapes Me Now the the
something Council I forget now
um where the you know the 25 or 30
senior most princes the the King dies
and then all the senior most princes get
together and they say okay well the next
brother becomes king so who's going to
become Crown Prince because they have
skipped Brothers some brothers have said
it's not this isn't for me I'd rather
I'd rather live in Paris you know or
London I I don't want to be the Crown
Prince and they say fine they just skip
them over so they they consult on all
these major Personnel decisions until
NBS NBS said no I'm the Crown Prince and
whoever doesn't like it is going to get
a bullet between the eyes and then he
actually did it yeah he grew up like
they never suspected he was going to be
that kid because he was like the spoiled
rich kid who played video games all the
time but what these guys were saying in
their book is that when he was a
teenager he would he had access to his
father so he would start to just sit in
on meetings and watch and he learned how
power was wielded yeah and picked up on
those things and the leap that I made
with this is that perhaps cuz he play
like he played a lot of video games like
they were saying like a lot and perhaps
because he went into these fake worlds
and he didn't have any stakes in his
life because he has everything he ever
wants he's a [__] there were some other
weird psychological things going on with
him like with punishments and stuff like
that like he would act weird but like I
think he got desensitized to the world
my guess through the video games and
kind of living within that and then saw
the application of power in the real
world and kind of mesh the two and he
doesn't feel anything he has absolutely
zero empathy he's he's a total sociopath
that's exactly what it is sociopathy I
was invited to a dinner once in Riad I
was serving there in 91 and um there was
this guy that I was friendly with at the
foreign Ministry he was just a fun nice
guy you know guy that you had a good
time hanging out with he invited me to
his house for dinner which was unusual
for a Saudi because I I got to meet his
wife she was unveiled and that was a
very big deal it really showed
friendship so we're invited to this
dinner and it's at one of the Palaces I
don't even remember was she hot no
no
no I love how you said that no poor guy
they were probably first cousins too in
retrospect
anyway um fad was the king he was not at
the dinner but there were a lot of
princes at the to dinner and he and I
went out onto the balcony he wanted to
smoke a cigarette we're out there
laughing and joking and and then this
big fat barrel of lard comes out onto
the balcony and he snaps to attention my
friend does and I recognized this kid as
AO he was Prince abdulaziz bin Fahad the
favorite son of King Fahad I had never
seen Aus before I'd seen pictures of
him he had to be 450 pounds it was
disgusting
whoa remind me to come back to that okay
in a second so one of the things about
Saudi culture is it's considered to be
effeminate to wear jewelry men don't
wear jewelry the only thing you're
allowed to wear is a wedding ring that's
it um so in order to show wealth or good
taste all Saudi men have a really good
watch and a really good pen so this guy
had like a $1,000 Waterman you know
whatever special pen he got in Geneva or
whatever and isus comes out and uh he
snaps to attention and he says your
majesty and I said uh I said hello
Prince uh Prince I didn't call him Aus
that was his nickname I I said hello
Prince Abal aiz I'm John kiraka from the
American Embassy didn't shake my hand
didn't even make eye contact with me and
Aus says I like your
pen and my friend says oh thank you and
he takes it out you know and looks at it
and isus saysi take it now and then just
takes it puts it in his own pocket and
then goes back into the
dinner and my friend is looking at me
and I said what a [__] [__]
that you didn't say that too loud did
you not too loud yeah I was gonna say
and he just shook his head I thought he
was going to cry but that's how these
guys are yeah they're used to [__]
on people yep and and you have to just
take it you said you wanted to come back
to the fact he was 450 AO was so
freaking fat they were all fat like this
it was ridiculous so when they renovated
dahon airport I was stationed in Bahrain
at the time this was 94 so it was three
years later when they renovated dahon
airport they had to special order double
wide
escalators because when these Saudi
royal family members would get on the
escalators they would have to stand
sideways because their asses couldn't
fit on the escalator so they're all
double wides oh it's a it's sorry and
it's just I would recommend people read
that book just cuz excellent yeah it's
it's a
wide it's crazy if you want sort of
deeper background of the royal family as
a family beginning with the fight to
consolidate um the Arabian Peninsula the
house of saoud is an absolute classic It
Was Written in the 80s yeah absolute
classic okay it was the first book I
read before my first trip to Saudi
Arabia when was your first trip there 91
90 90
you were and that was when you were the
Saddam Hussein historian for CIA right
were you going there on something
related to that yeah the Kuwaiti royal
family had been pushed out of Kuwait
from The Invasion and they were
relocated to TF right outside of Mecca
so I went to okay it's coming back to me
now babysit well John one one last thing
before we get out of here today one
topic we we can't leave hanging out
there is China because it's so you know
this one's like kind of a weird one
because it was like one of those things
you couldn't talk about like four years
ago or 5 years ago it's like don't talk
about China and then I'll never forget
this I've told this story a few times
but I was talking with Danny Jones this
is like June 2022 so the Ukraine the
Ukraine war it was three months four
months in just gotten started and I said
you know I saw something crazy today one
of the one of the you know kind of old
school General think tanks in DC posted
a scathing paper on China like huh and
this was also at a time where there were
some podcasts that were happening on our
shows where some guys were starting to
talk about China who had some
connections and they were doing it
pretty loudly and proudly and I'm like I
think this is going to shift and I'm
telling you overnight like it had
probably already started it suddenly
became like YouTube wanted that content
wow you know the platforms wanted that
and they were pushing the [__] out of it
wow really I look at China and I see
they got a huge GDP they got a huge
population they got a crazy government
they got a strong military and they're
buying a lot of soft power around I
might even call it hard power around the
world and the these are all problematic
but sometimes I do hearken back to the
is this just like we're trying to
overplay an enemy so that we have one so
we have something to focus on or do you
do you think that they're the full-blown
legit like threat to American
sovereignty through things like bricks
and stuff like that I think maybe it's
somewhere in the middle I hate to be I
hate to be wishy-washy about I like that
the reason I say that is because if you
look
historically Tibet aside
mhm the Chinese have never invaded
another country anywhere in the world
they had a border Skirmish with the
Indians they had a border Skirmish with
the Vietnamese that lasted a couple of
days H with the Indians it was longer a
couple of weeks but Tibet aside I say
Tibet aside because they the Chinese
genuinely believe Tibet is Chinese right
it's not inp depent shouldn't be an
independent country so they took it in
the 50s I think it was 53 and they kept
it um but the Chinese just don't
interfere militarily in other countries
they do have a very small base that
ironically they share with us in
Djibouti and there's like a fence down
the middle and this side is American and
that side is Chinese it's the weirdest
craziest thing that's got to be awkward
the Chinese have all their hanger doors
open and ours are closed and I said to
one of the guys I said hey how come ours
are closed what's in there and he's like
dude I can't tell you what's in there I
said I I know what's in there I'm just
pulling your leg so um anyway we don't I
don't think we need to worry about the
Chinese militarily not the way you hear
you know senators and congressmen
talking about it why not because they
just don't have an imperialist past
Place yeah now what we do have to worry
about very much is they are m Masters at
the use of soft power yes Masters Belton
Road initiative oh my God it's
absolutely brilliant and talk about a
country with a long-term view yes oh my
God they look decades and decades out
you know I'm a I'm a dual us Greek
citizen right I take my greekness and my
Greek citizenship very seriously so I'm
in Greece and the Greeks are having
these economic problems and people are
like [__] Chinese came and bought the
the port of perus the port of
Thessaloniki and the port of iron cre
that's what all my friends said too all
my Greek friends yeah they just they
just come in and buy everything oh we
don't want you guys to lose your jobs we
know you're broke we'll buy it and you
just keep working the way you work well
now everybody's indebted to the Chinese
yeah look every every Highway that's
been built in Africa in the last 10
years has been built by the chines yes
same thing in Yemen you know I remember
I remember the first time I was in Yemen
1991 the Chinese were building highways
there it's like thousands of Chinese and
they're all doing road
construction but they were using
Dynamite to to Dynamite through some
rock to build this road and the tribe
that they still had nomadic tribes there
they were they were furious at all this
noise and so one day this Chinese I
don't know what he was a corporate
leader the Ambassador
somebody some senior Chinese guy came in
a
helicopter and they're doing a ceremony
and dedicating the you know cutting the
ribbon and dedicating the highway and
here the tribe had tied ropes to the
helicopter and they tied the ropes to
like a dozen camels and they're dragging
the helicopter into the desert to punish
the Chinese for making all that noise
building the road whoa there's even a
monument on one of the hills over
looking saah uh it's a monument to the
Chinese Road workers who were killed by
tribesmen while they were building the
roads the yemenese had it up to here
with the Chinese sounds like it but then
the Africans were like hey you're
welcome to come here we're happy to take
your money and that work and they can't
pay it back no and the Chinese don't
expect it back but instead if you can't
pay it back how about yeah you let us
stay or you let us process all of your
rare earth metals cuz most of the rare
earth
metals that are that are mined are not
processed on site there's so much waste
involved that you can't make money but
the Chinese have so much money that
they're happy to take the loss on the
ore
processing because it sort of buys them
an in with the countries that mine it
you know you go to you go to Congo for
example or whatever they're calling it
now I guess it's Congo and the biggest
Embassy in the country is the Chinese
Embassy it's not the American Embassy or
the Russians used to be but it's the
Chinese yeah Africa is like Ground Zero
with this it is it's everywhere when you
talk with Shawn Ryan I want you to talk
with this about him or talk about this
with him we'll do because I I know like
he feels really strongly about this
stuff a couple years ago when he was on
my podcast we talked about it a bunch
he's like John is here John is there
John is everywhere they are and they are
and it's hard to deny that and it's like
it happened without anybody noticing and
then by the time the internet Community
noticed it's too late they're everywhere
and how do we roll that back we don't
know well we also like accept the fact
that they won't integrate our tech
companies in there but they integrate
all theirs here it's like this double
standard it is a double standard and
then there's even soft power with like
the weapons of the mine like you know
this is the one place where like the
Communism works I it makes me sick to
say that but like with their kids yeah
on their Tik Tok it [__] shuts off at
9:00 at night first of all and second
they're getting science videos and
they're getting like like good videos
here it's 24/7 and kids are getting
titty videos yes and and brain melting
videos oh my God so they're using our
freedom and democracy against itself and
in this one anecdotal example they're
using their lack of freedom for
themselves in a long-term investment
stuff like this bother and your earlier
point about fenel should not be
understated that's not an
accident I'm going to have this guy Ben
westof in here he did an amazing podcast
like probably six years ago with Joe
Rogan he wrote this book called fentel
Inc you ever see this no guy was like a
culture reporter not a reporter on any
of this stuff he was assigned some story
like in the music industry to cover and
while he's talking to some Source in the
story The guy offhand mentions fenel and
like what a problem it is and Ben had
heard of it but he's like ah tell me
more about it and very quickly he
realized holy [__] and he went down the
rabbit hole and he's a Savage this guy
Ben
bought a ticket to China like he's an
author himself and said let's let's just
see how easy it is to get fentel wow and
he like I'm I'm gonna let him tell the
full story when he comes in here but he
goes to like this full warehouse and
everything and they're like so you want
it in that package or you want it in
this package oh my God and then you see
that these guys are also working
directly with the cartels who can just
Chuck it across the border it's a
reverse Opium War oh my God and that's a
big problem yeah that's a big problem
mhm you think they're going to clean
that up
I'll tell you I think if anybody does
it's going to be Donald Trump yeah you
know a lot of people I think didn't
understand the import the full import of
declaring uh the Mexican cartels to be
terrorist groups that opens up a whole
bunch of presidential authorities and uh
lines of funding that otherwise would
have been unavailable to the military to
go after the fenel
trade can you explain that like how that
would work because this is I have some
guys coming in I was going to ask them
about it I still will but sure um you
know if if a an organization is declared
to be a clear and present danger to
American persons American installations
or the American government the president
can
order can order programs to be
implemented to oppose them without
necessitating Congressional approval you
can act quickly like Trump send the
military well he can send the military
without to get a congressional
authorization because the cartels are
now a terrorist group so it it opens
that Avenue you don't have to get it
bogged down in some debate on Capitol
Hill where they attach the perverted
Arts funding you know Amendment and you
need 60 votes in the Senate to break
cloer you just do it you got power yeah
you got power just do it and nobody
really talked about that which kind of
surprised me especially the DC based
press like Politico and the hill and
even the post they're usually right on
these kinds of
issues but I they weren't on this no I
think it was a good they were like oh my
God what's President shine Shin Bal
gonna say she's new and she's never had
to deal with Trump before and oh my God
they're not going to like us anymore in
Mexico it's like that wasn't the point
yeah that ship sailed yeah that was not
the
point also did you happen to notice that
border crossings have gone down to
almost zero
yeah I got to get more information on it
but certain the early the early reports
are that it's a lot better than it was
yeah pretty easy to be a lot better than
it was to be honest but the Democrats
just could not get it through their
thick skulls that the American people
wanted the border secure yeah and it's
like the most common sense thing it's
not hateful or anything I'll tell you
when I was when I was in Greece uh two
years ago um they they were having a
serious problem with the tur
the the Turks take billions of Euros
from the European Union to house
refugees okay they have refugees coming
from Syria from Iraq from Kurdistan from
all over the place Pakistan Afghanistan
thousands and thousands of people so the
EU gives them billions of Euros just
keep them in Turkey but what they do is
at night they push them across the
border into
Greece yeah in fact I was with my cousin
oh my God my cousin's a DJ on the island
of r heard by the way I've heard direct
stories from my guys in the Greek
military about that it's bad it's really
bad so my cousin he finishes his his gig
at this nightclub and he and I are
standing outside the nightclub just
closed it's like 2 2:30 in the morning
we're standing outside and it's right on
the beach and and this boat comes up it
just the it softly just kind of lands on
the beach and like 12 syrians get out
and we're looking at these guys and I I
I said to one of them and Wayne where
are you from Mina we're from Syria I go
are you
refugees and they said yeah and my
cousin he's he's a young guy he just
turned 30 he's like are you hungry and
they said yes and he said wait here I'll
get you food I'm like what he goes in
the club he comes out with these
sandwiches John's coming out with a
stick I know I'm like hey hey back to
turkey with
you so
um we told them you know we we had to
call the police because the police would
have to process them as refugees and so
the cops came down were very nice very
welcoming and everything was cool
because they they said it's not the
syrians fault no it's not they're
they're looking for a better life it's
the [__] Turks fault y because the
Turks are taking the money and still
pushing the refugees out so the point of
this is what the Greeks did you know
they don't have much of a land border
with turkey it's all in the north
everything is Islands the islands are
hard to patrol because there are like
you know 1100 Islands so what they did
is they built a wall like an actual
honest to God wall and the Turks jumped
up and down like across the water no no
on the land part of the Border in in
northern Greece not a single person
crosses that wall not a single one and
here's me like ah Trump he's lying he's
the Mexicans are going to pay for it and
then the Greek wall oh the Wall Works I
said I was wrong I was wrong about the
wall yeah it's crazy yeah it's listen I
got to give him credit on that the he
talked about it so simply which I think
was a turnoff but when you run the tape
in 2015 of what he was saying he was
right he was right on that for sure yes
he was and a lot of other more
importantly a lot of other people were
very wrong that's right you know and
[__] got crazy but John we be here all
night if we keep going across stuff I
think we just did two again this time so
this was [__] great great love having
you through glad to see you're getting
some speakers gigs than much so we'll
stick any links including to your
substack down below substack and unified
I do most my stuff in those two places
and listen if you're in uh in the UK
over the next two months I got like 44
speaking dates it's going to be at
tigersan studios.com all the info is
there we'll have that down below like
make Mark for those three links a lesson
we'll do that thank you thank you as
always sir thank you buddy all right
great everybody else you know what it is
give it a thought get back to me peace
thank you guys for watching the episode
if you haven't already please hit that
subscribe button and smash that like
button on the video they're both a huge
huge help and if you would like to
follow me on Instagram and X those links
are in my description below